<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-11-26T12:49:40-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">11-11</title><subtitle>Eleven Eleven was first published by California College of the Arts in 2003 as a journal of art and literature; since then it has been edited by faculty and students in the MFA in Writing program.</subtitle><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><entry><title type="html">Someone Quiet Down The Biodiverse “I”</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/someone-quiet-down-the-biodiverse/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Someone Quiet Down The Biodiverse “I”" /><published>2019-11-01T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-11-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/someone-quiet-down-the-biodiverse</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/someone-quiet-down-the-biodiverse/">&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 2;&quot;&gt;
Decentralize now
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This is our shared mission
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Sorry to change it again mom, but we’re giving up singular pronouns
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Sorry to change it again but we’re going by Anthropocene now
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Sorry but climate change is real and it &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; caused by human activity
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Sorry to change it again but your ‘spirit animal’ has gone extinct
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Sorry to change it again but the planet is really purging us
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
So sorry to interrupt
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Sorry but 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Sorry we
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Sorry
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- End of page --&gt;
&lt;!-- Start of Bottom Footer --&gt;

&lt;nav class=&quot;nav justify-content-center&quot; style=&quot;box-shadow: 0 2px 2px -2px rgba(0,0,0,0);&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;nav-container&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;//&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h2 class=&quot;nav-title&quot;&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul style=&quot;position: relative&quot;&gt;
      &lt;!-- &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;//&quot;&gt;Issue&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; --&gt;
      &lt;li class=&quot;nav-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;nav-link&quot; href=&quot;//2018-fall&quot;&gt;2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li class=&quot;nav-item&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;|&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li class=&quot;nav-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;nav-link&quot; href=&quot;//2019-fall&quot;&gt;2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li class=&quot;nav-item&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;|&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li class=&quot;nav-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;nav-link&quot; href=&quot;//people&quot;&gt;People&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li class=&quot;nav-item&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;|&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li class=&quot;nav-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;nav-link&quot; href=&quot;//about&quot;&gt;About&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/nav&gt;

&lt;section id=&quot;sec4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//timothy-morton/&quot;&gt;Timothy Morton&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//fullness-of-being/&quot;&gt;FULLNESS of BEING&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//oliver-bendorf/&quot;&gt;Oliver Baez Bendorf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//cheers/&quot;&gt;Cheers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//someone-quiet-down-the-biodiverse/&quot;&gt;Someone Quiet Down The Biodiverse “I”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/section&gt;</content><author><name>Oliver Baez Bendorf</name></author><category term="20191111" /><summary type="html">Decentralize now This is our shared mission Sorry to change it again mom, but we’re giving up singular pronouns Sorry to change it again but we’re going by Anthropocene now Sorry but climate change is real and it is caused by human activity Sorry to change it again but your ‘spirit animal’ has gone extinct Sorry to change it again but the planet is really purging us So sorry to interrupt Sorry but Sorry we Sorry 2018 | 2019 | People | About Timothy Morton FULLNESS of BEING Oliver Baez Bendorf Cheers Someone Quiet Down The Biodiverse “I”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Fullness of Being</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/fullness-of-being/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fullness of Being" /><published>2019-11-01T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-11-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/fullness-of-being</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/fullness-of-being/">&lt;p&gt;Public lecture delivered April, 2019, to culminate the first ECOPOESIS gathering at California College of the Arts, San Francisco&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“The idea that alienation is being cut off from the future, the possibility that things might be different, has become very easy to think, and very good to think. All this has some consequences for art.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 2;&quot;&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 5em; font-weight: 500;display:inline-block&quot;&gt;“&lt;/span&gt;Most ecological and plenty of non-ecological theories of alienation exist. Most of them state that we are alienated from a past where things were better, or perfect. But this is just the notion of the Fall, translated into some other mode, and that narrative is one way in which agricultural societies talk about the damage they have already done. The inherent speciesism (“nature” versus human culture) of this model is historically bankrolled by racism and patriarchy.
There’s another way of thinking about alienation, logically, and luckily there are ways of showing that it’s true: if we aren’t alienated from the past we are alienated from the future.
The media tell us that we are approaching the end of the world, because of global warming, but it’s much more serious than that. We are approaching us being dead and children now growing up and having to live in this biosphere, for a long time—longer than the end of time, in any case. The idea that alienation is being cut off from the future, the possibility that things might be different, has become very easy to think, and very good to think.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
All this has some consequences for art.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;d style=&quot;padding-left: 50px;&quot;&gt;What happens to a dream deferred?&lt;/d&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;d style=&quot;padding-left: 100px;&quot;&gt;Does it dry up&lt;/d&gt;
&lt;d style=&quot;padding-left: 100px;display:block&quot;&gt;like a raisin in the sun?&lt;/d&gt;
&lt;d style=&quot;padding-left: 100px;display:block&quot;&gt;Or fester like a sore—&lt;/d&gt;
&lt;d style=&quot;padding-left: 100px;display:block&quot;&gt;And then run?&lt;/d&gt;
&lt;d style=&quot;padding-left: 100px;display:block&quot;&gt;Does it stink like rotten meat?&lt;/d&gt;
&lt;d style=&quot;padding-left: 100px;display:block&quot;&gt;Or crust and sugar over—&lt;/d&gt;
&lt;d style=&quot;padding-left: 100px;display:block&quot;&gt;like a syrupy sweet?&lt;/d&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;d style=&quot;padding-left: 100px;display:block&quot;&gt;Maybe it just sags&lt;/d&gt;
&lt;d style=&quot;padding-left: 100px;display:block&quot;&gt;like a heavy load.&lt;/d&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;d style=&quot;padding-left: 100px;display:block&quot;&gt;Or does it explode?&lt;/d&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This is a poem called “Harlem” and it’s by Langston Hughes. Let’s start to read it.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;Okay, well who wrote this poem? Langston Hughes would be the easiest answer. But all kinds of author functions, as Foucault used to say, exist. Maybe it’s better to say “Who or what wrote the poem?” It’s quite common for example to reduce Marxist criticism to its vulgar version, where you square the poem with the economic conditions of the day, say about a decade, in the country in which it was written. That Tennyson poem is a typical product of 1840s industrial capitalism in Britain. This Hughes poem is a typical product of 1950s American capitalism. Or whatever.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;
So who wrote the poem? A human being? The human being’s family or psychic issues? The human being’s unconscious? The culture the human lived in? How many do we include? Who wrote the poem? Capitalism? The human genome? The biosphere? The ecosystem around the human poet? A light fall of rain one morning? The climate? The nuclear industry? The military industrial complex? The structure of racism in mid-twentieth century America? The struggle of African Americans to achieve basic rights?
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;
You see the thing is, ecological awareness is all about beginning to realize that things are happening on all kinds of scales, all at once, and that these scales aren’t like how you encounter them in museums or online. You can’t toggle nicely and smoothly back and forth from the very small to the very large, from the micro to the macro. That micro macro talk is Neoplatonic medieval something or other anyway.
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;
All right, let’s try something else. When was the poem written? The early twentieth century? The week Hughes put pen to paper? The month?  One year in his life? The time of modernity? The time of modernism? The time of post-Neolithic civilization? The time of humans on Earth?
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;
In a way the poem was written in all of these times. Right? Just like in a way, all the beings I listed earlier wrote the poem.
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;
Let’s think about another aspect of the poem. Let’s think about the physical media of which it’s composed. Paper, typewriter ink; pixels, glass screens; microfilm. Roman Jakobson has a clunky but interesting six-part model of communication, that is useful in the way that all structuralist interpretative devices are useful, which is the way in which magic mixers that can slice and dice your food five different ways are useful. Put the poem through the blender, you learn something from what the blender does to it.
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;
So the first thing you notice is, there are these spacious gaps between some of the lines, while some other lines are close together. The first line, “What happens to a dream deferred?” has a lot of space around it—it’s trying to make you think, but it’s also trying to make you feel something, the opaque weight of all that deferment. It’s a tight little poem, whose lines have two or three rhythmical feet, and that means that unlike a wall of words, the space around the poem and between the stanzas is highlighted and becomes part of how you read it—you have to find some way to pronounce the blankness at the end of each line. In a way the poem a little bit lonely, like discarded little carton of orange juice that you find one day lying in an empty parking lot—not enough people are noticing what it’s saying. Or, conversely, the poem is trapped in a bath of blankness, pressing in on all sides—if you think about the parking lot the same way, it’s the same thing. something huge and constructed and blank yet weirdly invisible because it’s so hard to see presses in on our powers of thought and our physical powers on all sides. Your feet ache and you feel lonely and you regret the absence of butterflies.
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;
(The poem isn’t going to tell you. Poems let themselves be opaque altogether, like that parking lot, or we let them, or both. That means that poems are a place where what I like to call the future future gathers—the radical freshness that enables the possibility that things might be different, rather than the one we can build out from where we are now, using prediction and extrapolation. Again, my point is that we are alienated from the future, not from the past. we aren’t trying to recover an Edenic meaning that the poet somehow hid in there like a message in a bottle. We’re trying to assess the scope and awesomeness of this particular futural gateway.)
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;
The weight  of deferment—the weight of waiting, as a matter of fact—is legible in the way the poem organizes the medium in which it has been inscribed—the so called “space” is actually the obtruding presence of the physical medium in which the poem exists. Say it’s on paper, well in that case, there’s a lot of pulp, trees, water, sunlight, all the things that make trees that make paper, in that pause. It’s not nothing. It’s not silence, as John Cage would have said—silence is just the way socially determined sounds taper off and you get to hear something else.
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;
It’s something I love about the Laser Interferometry Gravitational Observatory, about two miles north west of New Orleans, which is sort of Houston’s sister city. Two laser beams at right angles. It’s a very simple and relatively cheap experiment, compared at any rate with CERN. It’s tens of millions rather than billions, and there’s a difference, although it may seem absurdly expensive to us. At LIGO, these two lasers are bouncing off carefully calibrated mirrors. They pick up everything. Everything. Like cattle walking over the cattle grid in the field outside. People having arguments in an adjoining room about the experiment. Cars going past on the road outside. And you know what’s most uncanny is, if you know the waveforms for these things, you can subtract them from the waveform that results from the vibrating lasers. The movement of tectonic plates; the sound of aircraft…the lasers pick up everything, and when you cut out those cows walking over the grid and so on (I love the cows part), and there’s a tiny squiggle of something left, that you can’t explain, and it has the right sort of anticipated shape, do you know what is? That thing is a gravity wave.
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;
It’s a signature of two black holes colliding, one thousand light years away, a tiny flicker of spacetime in which everything on Earth got a little bit smaller and a little bit slower-living, then a little bit bigger and a little bit faster, then back to normal. Half an hour after the new improved LIGO was switched on, with more carefully calibrated lasers, two black holes collided and the energy equaled the output of the entire universe. And a ripple in spacetime spread out until it passed through everything on Earth. Is it not uncanny—rather like the idea of shadowtime that I was hearing about yesterday evening—that the gravity wave was right there, inside the waveform determined by moocows, cars, people arguing, tectonic plates…
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;d style=&quot;padding-left: 100px;display:block&quot;&gt;Does [the dream deferred] stink like rotten meat?&lt;/d&gt;
&lt;d style=&quot;padding-left: 100px;display:block&quot;&gt;Or crust and sugar over—&lt;/d&gt;
&lt;d style=&quot;padding-left: 100px;display:block&quot;&gt;like a syrupy sweet?&lt;/d&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;d style=&quot;padding-left: 100px;display:block&quot;&gt;Maybe it just sags&lt;/d&gt;
&lt;d style=&quot;padding-left: 100px;display:block&quot;&gt;like a heavy load.&lt;/d&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;d style=&quot;padding-left: 100px;display:block&quot;&gt;Or does it explode?&lt;/d&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;
Then you realize that the shadowtime is also in the imagery. The rotting of meat—the way it becomes inedible for humans because it’s being eaten by bacteria—the rotting is commensurate, in a metaphorical sense, with the deferment of the dream of un-alienated fullness of being, the “dream” that Hughes is talking about. It’s an ecological process—the appropriation of something we thought was just for us (it’s called “meat” not “cows” or “pigs” for this reason), by something else. The something else-ness is what makes the rottenness of the meat disgusting. That’s a thing that can happen in a few days in your kitchen; the racism is a thing that can happen for several hundred years in the hemisphere you live in on Earth. Metaphor is bringing these two timescales close without collapsing them into one another. “This is that,” in the realm of metaphor rather than math, means also that “this is not that.” Rotting time is not the same as dream deferment time.
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;
Then there’s the “crust”-ing and the “sugar”-ing over. Perhaps Hughes means that the dream becomes a candified, plastic, purely aesthetic version of itself, easy to understand but impossible to act out, because it’s been reduced to a commodified consumer object. Given the long history of slavery and sugar, this is a potent image indeed. The Romantic poets Coleridge and Southey argued for boycotting sugar in the mid 1790s, arguing that sugar was an extreme metaphor or catachresis: sugar is the crystallized blood of slaves. The implication in the image is that the sugar coating would be a symptom of continuing slavery. If sugar is alienated slave labor, a sugar-coated dream is an alienated one that you can’t realize, only appreciate.
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;
The sick part of the sugaring is that the dream might do it to itself, like how chocolate starts to separate and the ingredients rise and sink, something we call chocolate bloom. The sweetness of the dream might rise to the surface, encrust it and make it impossible to live it. The oppressive forces are installed inside of the dream, because the dream is in relation to them, and is born within them. And in an ecological context, if, as I believe, destroying racism would be tantamount to undoing a gigantic amount of the ideologies that sever us from other lifeforms, a severing actively and automatically pursued for thousands of years in what is called civilization, the response to the mid global warming of the Holocene—if destroying racism means that, then “Harlem” is talking obliquely about an ecological politics.
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;
Let’s talk about that for a moment—what I mean by that. Economics isn’t about dollars and interest rates. Dollars and interest rates aren’t about dollars and interest rates. All that stuff is reified capitalist theology, aka economics 101 in non-communist universities. Economics is how you organize your enjoyment, how you organize how stuff flows around in your house, your home, your world, all the shit that you have going on.
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;
And ecology is how the house, the home, the world that you’ve got going works, the logic of it. Economics and ecology are intertwined, etymologically, logically, socially, everything. So the question is, do these things pertain only to human beings? Do you have cockroaches and rats in or around your home? Do you look after a cat, and is it your house the cat lives in? Since I leave the house a lot more than the cat, in many ways it’s the cat’s house more than mine. This is sort of related to how, when I became a dad, I had that this is not my beautiful house feeling, very quickly, as Claire began to make it very clear that it was her house, not mine—psychologically that’s very true, isn’t it, your parents’ house that you grew up in was much more yours than theirs, it was the first world you lived in. They just happened to rent or buy or whatever another living space in a series.
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;
And related to this question, another question of pleasure. If we don’t like the theology of dollars and structural unemployment and having to work to live and all that stuff—if we think we are a bit socialist or Marxist or anarcho-communist whatever—do we think it would be a good idea to include cockroaches and cats in the revolutionary projects we have going on to transmogrify our homes, our worlds, into things that are more pleasurable for the beings who have stuff going on, like trying to find out where the rats really live in my cat’s case, or trying to write a lecture when you’re feeling really depressed about ecological politics and mass extinction in my case, etc?
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;
From a utilitarian point of view—which I find deeply problematic but whatever let’s use it, because it’s pretty default in our world—just existing is a form of pleasure. So if there are more revolutionary beings, like hedgehogs with little Che Guevara caps and stuff, that means more pleasure, so involving more lifeforms in revolutionary struggles would be better. Thanks very much for listening, my name is Tim Morton and if you have any questions I’ll be available afterwards.
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;
Right. So let’s go back to the poem. There’s the stuff about the dream rotting or glazing itself with sugar. I like very much how the dream immediately is a physical thing, something lying around in the sun. Then there’s another gap, and the idea that the dream might just continue, in an abject sort of way, “sagging” “Like a heavy load”—the dream itself has lost its utopian dreamlike lightness and has itself become one of the things that hangs over your head.
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;
In writing this poem, the authors (for Langston Hughes is one of them, but there are many that his work brings into alignment) seem to be observing that a whole complex range of timescales and histories are felt in the deferment of the dream, whose lingering potency is present in its absence in the way the poem organizes the blank space around it.
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;
But the blank space isn’t blank. The poem obviously plays with topics such as rotting and producing sugars, or being coated by sugars, processes that are to do with the biochemistry of lifeforms in a biosphere. The gaps in the poem mean that something there, but what is there? The open question quality is legible in the opacity of those gaps. What is there quite literally is the paper or the pixels, and what is there definitely and more figuratively is the labor of black people—what Karl Marx would call the species being of humans. Marx identifies this with imaginative projection and appropriation, but we don’t have to. Let’s just focus on the brute, aka silent, presence of physical being in those gaps, a physical being whose analog are the concrete images of rotting, sugaring and exploding.
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;
What is this physical being? The work of slaves, thought in typical western philosophy as a machinic functioning, like the behavior of an algorithm. Slavery articulates the anthropocentric differences between humans and so-called animals: humans, like slave owners, act, while animals, like slaves, merely behave. You can see immediately that the ways we have of talking about this stuff are deeply contaminated by speciesism, and that this has to do with racism, and I’m going to try to sort out exactly how in this talk. Because blank space isn’t just blank, and because the physical medium the poem appears in doesn’t just function smoothly in the background. That’s the whole point—the obtrusion of the paper or pixels into the poem itself is a kind of malfunction, like rotting or sugaring or sagging, and perhaps like exploding: that’s the question the poem poses altogether—is the exploding an error? We know it’s the logical consequence, within the poem, of continuing oppression. But does “explode” mean “explode into life and therefore become dangerous to the white powers that be” or does “explode” mean “evaporate as if it had never existed at all”?
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;
The blank space is and isn’t the poem. It’s a place where the poem malfunctions or rather, a place where the poem reveals that one being’s functioning is another being’s malfunction, and more deeply, how lines of poetry and spaces between them and everything else are all a series of malfunctions, such that smoothness is an illusion. Indeed, the deferment and the supposed silence are symptoms of a massive malfunction, in the fully “evil” sense of “mal” as the first syllables of that word. An evil functioning is what is detected in the gaps in the poem, the persistence of a state that has indeed been naturalized—the relations between white and black people—but which is anything but natural; or rather, the smoothness of its supposed naturalness is in fact a symptom of horrific violence, like the peaceful atmosphere after a tornado or bomb test.
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;
And isn’t that ecological awareness in a nutshell, really? The fact that since there is always an environment—some kind of opacity, some kind of surrounding something in which things are taking place—that the silence and absence isn’t to do with the reader being stupid or evil. Environmental awareness isn’t about being smarter or wiser than the average person. It’s just how awareness in general is, that it always takes place against some kind of taken for granted structure or background or set of assumptions or rows of beehives or vineyards or sugar plantations…there’s always a shadow side, always a shadowtime—it’s not that if you’re truly ecological there are no shadows. It’s that there are more. You are more haunted than you were.
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;
Ecological awareness most certainly is not about seeing things more clearly than Joe Public. Ecological awareness is about being willing to be haunted. We’ll see quite soon just how hard wired into ecology are concepts of specters, ghosts, shadows, fleeting things that appear in the corner of your eye. Ecologica awareness doesn’t mean you exorcised the bad artificial stuff and got back to nature. It mean that a greater number than ever of opaque semi-silent shadowy beings are making soft noises in the margins...it’s something that is powerfully conveyed in Amiri Baraka’s “Something in the Way of Things,” a poem whose paranoid tone aims to delineate the spooky, spectral presence of brutality and exploitation and racism in the fabric of the seemingly quiet street along which the narrator is walking.
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;
Paranoia is the default, ground state version of empathy—the more paranoid I am about you, are you really a robot or not, is the way I become more and more interested in you as a person. This whole idea that people are beings who obviously act and animals are beings who obviously behave, like robots, is theological and extreme, and, as I’m already starting to argue if you can feel it, racist. Ecological awareness is not about making other people feel stupid. It’s about realizing that because there’s at least one shadowy corner around which you’re not seeing, you yourself are always stupid.
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;
The shadows are infinite because we don’t know in advance how many there are, not because they go on forever. It’s all shadows. The dreams of dead people, waiting to be fulfilled by the living. All the entities that the poem gathers—African American humans, white people, cows and sheep and paper and pixels, all these beings coexist in ways that overlap. You could say for example that the human species is a heap of things such as humans and cows and computers and ideas about knitting and feudal monarchy and sand. And beaches are a heap of things such as sand and humans and waves and seaweed and so on. If you think of the world in terms of hyperobjects you are thinking of the world in terms of lots of gigantic overlapping things that are finite and fuzzy. Who wrote the poem is a heap of inconsistent things. When the poem was written is a heap of inconsistent times.
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;
And if you like ecological beings such as meadows and beaches and nice city streets with people being decent together, you had better believe in heaps. Logic, traditional vanilla Western logic that is, makes it almost impossible to believe in heaps. You can take bits out of a heap while still calling it a heap, until there’s nothing left, whereupon you realize that there must be no such things as heaps because look, here’s a whole lot of nothing and you were assuming there was a heap right up to that point. It’s called the Sorites paradox. Clouds, according to this, don’t really exist, because they’re made of little bits of cloud stuff; when you subtract the cloud stuff you get smaller and smaller bits of cloud stuff until there’s nothing—so there are no clouds, because clouds are vague. In the same way, you can argue that the Amazon jungle is just a gigantic feedlot waiting to happen, because if you take trees away there’s still a jungle, and you can keep on going till there’s just one tree, so jungles don’t really exist.
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;
But perhaps being vague is a criterion for existing. It certainly doesn’t seem easy to get rid of vague and downright contradictory things, without tying yourself in knots. Furthermore, you have to be a holist of some kind to be ecological. The trouble is, most forms of holism are exclusive and explosive. What do I mean? I mean that maybe we need to think that wholes are vague and messy and contradictory, not like Pan Man beings that eat up their contents and digest them totally. A cow could be part of one hyperobject—the human species thought in a non-essentialist way—and part of another one—the cow species for example, which in an expanded way also includes grass.
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;
The last time western philosophy tried to talk about all of whatever we are at once it got it very wrong and said “white man” all the time, like scratch the surface of any human and you’ll find a white man underneath. But humans caused global warming, not dolphins. We had better have an idea of who we are that is real and up to date and not racist or patriarchal. Thinking of ourselves as part of a vague heap of things that aren’t all to do with us exclusively, whoever we think we are, is a good place to start. There really are wholes, but they’re not your grandaddy’s whole, all perfect and fully integrated.
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;
Otherwise the whole called human is a totally different world from the world called moocows, and so we might get to thinking that we can do what we want with moocows or just totally ignore them. If we can’t overlap, we can’t communicate. If the concept of word means something self-contained and rigid, there’s no hope at all. And someone can say “My concept of world is much richer than yours, or you don’t have one at all, so I own Australia now.”
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;
I reckon this vacuum sealed world concept comes from rigid class hierarchies and I reckon that comes from demarcating the difference between human and nonhuman space using things like walls, because you have created granaries to preserve food from the ravages of mild global warming. You sealed off your human survival temporality, so you justify this by getting to think in various ways that the seal demarcates something real (religion, tragedy, philosophy, however you do it). It’s about 10 000 BCE, and you’re doing the right thing, at your scale, just like how starting your car in the morning doesn’t cause global warming. No, it really doesn’t. you’re not guilty. Besides, eating a bit less meat is much, much more effective than buying a Tesla, and easier too.
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;
You justify the demarcations and divisions of labor by explaining that the other classes must be different, really, really different beings altogether. And this is how racism begins to function. And it’s that internal human division that enables speciesism, the imagined difference between humans and everyone else. Think of that great diagram in robotics design, the Uncanny Valley. It explains racism while being racist in itself, so it’s very good to analyze, so we can come up with something else.
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;
On one side of the valley is a very suspicious being, the so-called “healthy human being,” and I think we can all hear the normal vs pathological, eugenics resonance in that concept. Exactly what is that, I don’t wonder for more than a second, speaking as we are close to Sacramento where in the early twentieth century horrible eugenics experiments were carried out, such as leaving newborn babies to die in hospital because they were unfit. On the other side of the valley is a cute so-called animal, or their electornic equivalent, the cute droid such as R2D2. They’re cute because they’re different—they’re separated by a thin hard line, which is what the Uncanny Valley looks like when you look across it at R2D2, because of foreshortening. Hitler was fond of his dog Blondi because Blondi was different enough from him, so that he could feel all those nice sublimated cute aggression feelings and make animal rights legislation. Let’s just face it—a lot of environmental organizations have had deep connections with white supremacy, and I’m explaining why.
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;
The Uncanny Valley diagram was created because it became well known in robotics that as you came closer and closer to imitating a lifelike human being, the robot passed through a phase that appeared strange or scary or creepy. The ultimate nadir of the Uncanny Valley is the zombie, the animated corpse who is a parody of the Cartesian self, just a body animated by some invisible force, moving in an automated way like the brooms in the Sorcerer’s Apprentice. According to hicks I overheard in rural Colorado (!), the zombie apocalypse is a pretty obviously racist concept about hordes of nonwhite people coming for your property, Barbara, and what’s awesome about many zombie works of art is how they subvert that.
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;
Anyway, the nice cute difference between me and R2D2 or Blondi the Alsatian is enabled by all the beings labeled as inhuman, subhuman and so on, beings that racism has chucked into the Uncanny Valley. Speciesism—the rigid difference between a human and a nonhuman—is enabled by racism—the machinery that categorizes some beings as inhuman or subhuman. Until you find out that you are in fact Neanderthals in some way, you tell yourself that they are uncanny failed versions of humans who just behaved like zombies, unlike us who have imagination and can see round corners and figure out how to make the zombies go extinct by slaughtering them all. So the way out of the Valley is actually not to get rid of the uncanny, which would make everything into a cute little machine coexisting in some fascist medium, we are all Earthlings or whatever, but actually the way out is to jump into the Valley, to realize that we ourselves are uncanny beings, that being a lifeform at all is being uncanny, because you are strangely strange all the way down. Because you are a symbiotic product of a truly random series of mutations called evolution. Which means that there is no Valley, because there is no healthy human being or perfect cute R2D2. Ecological awareness is like realizing you are on a gigantic flat plain on which exist all kinds of hazy weird beings whose status as alive or not alive, sentient or not sentient, conscious or not conscious (and even existing or not-existing) is not settled, but disturbed at every point. Again, ecological awareness doesn’t mean you stuck your head in a tree and forgot all your problems. It means you allowed yourself to be more haunted than ever, and in particular, that founding religious difference between act and behave that gives you humans versus everything else, imagination versus computing, let there be light versus being a slave, and all that toxic stuff, that act/behave boundary is not erased so that everything is a machine (which means there is still a perfume of act versus behave going on somewhere), but that everything is profoundly ambiguous. You can’t tell whether I am an android or not, and that’s what makes you treat me like a person. You don’t have to prove that rocks are definitely alive, you just have to notice that “alive” or “conscious” means I’m paranoid that you might be a zombie. Coexisting in symbiosis means you might have swallowed poison, and you did—it’s called being alive, which kills you in the end.
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;
There was no true difference between you and the cats and the vultures. The difference was enabled by difference between yourself and other humans.
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;
So what is the basic tone of a reality in which being haunted is the basic background to everything? This is the same as the reality in which the possibility that you might have poisoned yourself by eating that berry happens. The wondering whether you have been poisoned is the internal version of wondering what is around that corner. What do we call that tone? Well, it’s great, because we name it after the Greek for everything. We call it Panic. The Great God Pan and the Pan quality, which we call panic.
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;
Panic then really means everythingness, the realization that everything is happening. But everything-feel isn’t a lovely total thing. Everything means that there are so many incommensurate levels, so many shadows, so many specters. I like the word panic here because it also suggests a kind of quivering movement. Panic isn’t static—it tends to rush around or at least shiver on its own somewhere.
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;
We are beginning to notice that true fullness in the end is movement, always expanding, expansiveness…fullness of being isn’t some static thing to be achieved, but a dynamic process. Marx says it’s really like how production is actually the same as consumption, which by the way is the best way to start thinking about Marxist readings of poems, not as reflections of the freakin economy in which they were supposedly written. Plucking an apricot and putting it to your nose so you can smell that rose scent just after it’s fallen off a tree, then putting it in your mouth, chewing, swallowing…all that stuff is production. If that doesn’t speak volumes about the ways “act” and “behave” or “suffer” or “experience” have been violently severed and with violent consequences, I don’t know what would. Even in Marx—sorry to the Hegelian Marxist in Langston Hughes—produce doesn’t mean “let there be light” or pulling a rabbit out of a hat. It means something much more like “appreciate” or even “consume.” In one letter, Marx says that humans begin by production, “that is,” he says immediately, “by eating and drinking.” To eat or drink something you have to go along with it. If you’re a single celled organism, you have to envelop it…gulp! OMG did I just swallow poison? Again, this is the default phenomenology of symbiosis, a radical hospitality, giving rise to the possibility that the guest we let in might destroy us.
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;
To sag is to sink or subside gradually…think about how all the stuff that might happen to the dream has a really different temporality to it. Rotting is what happens to a corpse and one can’t help but visualize the history of lynching and the song “Strange Fruit.” Becoming glazed with sugar might take longer than rotting, if we were thinking about an item of food. Sagging has to do with just persisting but without being used by us. And exploding might be the sudden catastrophe that results when sagging has gone on for a while, or glazing, or rotting. (**)
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;
What we are experiencing in this poem is discarded, unutilized pleasure. What is wrong with society, according to this logic, is not that there is too much pleasure in capitalism or consumerism. It’s that there’s not enough. Look—you just chucked that carton of juice away and you hadn’t even finished it. Now we have to get in the car and go to the water park, and you’ll be thirsty. It’s hard perhaps to deal with, in an ecology talk, in a country whose growth in the nineteenth century was a way to enact the fantasies of working class European immigrants, so that when you walk down Main Street, you are walking inside their heads—the heads that imagine what those rich posh people must be eating while you’re starving on potatoes: all the meat and white bread they must be eating, eventually turned into easy to handle hamburgers, the Land of Cockaygne “All you can eat,” big gulp fantasy that has done a great job so far of almost destroying Earth, America, the biggest pile of Europe ever—a place where by the side of the road you might find a gigantic shoe not made by Claes Oldenburg but by some local guy, the biggest this, the most amount of that, eventually requiring feedlots and planet death.
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;
It’s hard to swallow for us eco people, brought up on the necessity—and let’s face it the stylistic distinction—of being abstemious. It’s hard to swallow that what ecological politics might be about is more pleasure and not less, and that thus in consumerism there is a distorted not fully nice version of the kind of pleasure we might expect if, say, keeping polar bears or coral alive was higher up on our agenda. But that’s exactly the imagery in this poem—if you don’t try to enact it, the dream could rot or bloom with sugar or sag and explode, scattering its possibilities and causing unintended damage—and I suggest that since it’s a key, major part of the poetics of anti-racism and the struggle of African American people, and since this struggle is key to an ecological politics, we shouldn’t ignore that imagery.
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;
The poem is talking about interpretation, in lots of ways. The dream deferred is, as I pointed out earlier, the full meaning of the poem, which haunts the sentences like a shadow from the future. Dreams are like that, says Freud: they are infinitely interpretable. But what does infinity mean? If you try to count up to it, you won’t be able to, so the idea that it means “going on and on forever” is a dangerous illusion, an ideological one I would argue. Infinity means you can’t count it. There might be three of whatever it is, but you can’t know that in advance. There might be twenty million, but a thing stops somewhere. Interpretation stops somewhere. Alan Turing had to invent the idea of computers to prove that things stop somewhere. You can’t make a program powerful enough to predict when every other program will go into an infinite loop.
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;
Turing was trying to prove Gödel’s Incompleteness Theorem. A logical system must be flawed in order to exist so you can make it go into an infinite loop. And you can’t design an uber meta program that can predict (aka the future…) when any other algorithm will go into an infinite loop…which means that the future is open, like how poems are, because there must always be some opacity in a logical system in order for it to be transparent, or true. Godel created his theorem because about Russell and Whitehead were trying to police mathematician Cantor (a mathematician like Godel), police him with logic. Cantor discovered infinities that were ‘bigger” than regular. And infinity truly means you can’t count (compute) it, not it goes on forever…in between Hilbert was wondering whether computational processes could be seen to stop (the Entscheidungsproblem)…it’s like they invented computers to prove that computers can’t do everything…and then the Max 8 showed up…
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;
And in parallel this war between logic and math halfway through the twentieth century, like “Harlem,” like the Golden Spike in global warming data that scientists point to in 1945, this war between logic and math is about Tarski inventing the idea of metalanguage to police sentences like “this sentence is false”—you can always invent a sentence that will blow up the rule…like how Lacan says there is no metalanguage…
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;
The infinite openness of futurality is what the essence of a thing is, as opposed to its appearance, which is if you think about it the past. Automated systems such as economies or programs that make planes crash are past states of thought and feeling encoded in rules, customs, habits, lines of code. The trouble with automation is not artificial intelligence—heaven knows I may be an android. The trouble with automation is that the past is eating the future. Automation, if the past sucked, and generally it does, can you tell?—means alienation.
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;
Openness and finitude thus go together. Another way of saying what the mathematicians are saying against the western logicians, is that there’s at least one level on which you or your interpretation or your action, whatever it may be, suck(s). Some lifeform you didn’t think about gets killed or eventually you get cancer because you ate too many of whatever in whatever particular way. Ecological awareness, meaning you realize things happen on lots of space and time scales at once, means knowing that at some point at least you are a hypocrite. You can’t get it perfect. Not knowing when an entity wil come to an end is thus part of panic, the basic ecological mood, the great god Pan. You that a thing is flawed, that it will stop, but you can’t know exactly when or how, at least not for everything. Will mass extinction wipe us out, and when? It’s like that. It’s a good time to panic and think and do something about it.
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;
Sugar is a thing that evokes both Nature and culture, civilization and barbarism, pleasure and slavery. And in Hughes’s poem, a sugary death is only one way of thinking about the dream. The poem explodes the difference between coating a thing with sugar and letting that thing glaze itself—culture and nature. Nature and culture both now explode in the face of ecological awareness, evaporating in the face of what I like to call the symbiotic real—the fact of being in a biosphere where exorbitant and always risky mutual aid is in effect everywhere. The blankness of the page is the automated zombie apocalypse—it’s whiteness eating your brain with memes, stopping you from thinking, obtruding on the dream like a huge hot parking lot surrounding a carton of orange juice.
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;
Sagging suggests just letting gravity, aka spacetime, do its thing, a kind of existing in indifference. It’s not about stasis--it’s moving. Sagging is an abject movement that could indeed explode from the inside as slime as much as fire, like ectoplasm, the spectral body fluid; sagging is about physical being and time, “going out of shape” and getting old…Environmental creepiness is there in that racist southern gothic mood, half detected in “Harlem” and fully there in “Strange Fruit,” the weight of the past sagging or weighing like a nightmare. The futurality of things (the dream deferred) could sag in the toxic atmosphere of automation…the plane that can’t crash, the ship that can’t sink—didn’t we learn anything from the Titanic or from Titanic? Leonardo di Caprio would be pulped in a malfunctioning Max 8, that massively distributed Titanic. You can’t even make a romantic film about it. Is that progress? 
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- End of page --&gt;
&lt;!-- Start of Bottom Footer --&gt;

&lt;nav class=&quot;nav justify-content-center&quot; style=&quot;box-shadow: 0 2px 2px -2px rgba(0,0,0,0);&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;nav-container&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;//&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h2 class=&quot;nav-title&quot;&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul style=&quot;position: relative&quot;&gt;
      &lt;!-- &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;//&quot;&gt;Issue&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; --&gt;
      &lt;li class=&quot;nav-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;nav-link&quot; href=&quot;//2018-fall&quot;&gt;2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li class=&quot;nav-item&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;|&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li class=&quot;nav-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;nav-link&quot; href=&quot;//2019-fall&quot;&gt;2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li class=&quot;nav-item&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;|&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li class=&quot;nav-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;nav-link&quot; href=&quot;//people&quot;&gt;People&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li class=&quot;nav-item&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;|&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li class=&quot;nav-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;nav-link&quot; href=&quot;//about&quot;&gt;About&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/nav&gt;

&lt;section id=&quot;sec4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//timothy-morton/&quot;&gt;Timothy Morton&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//fullness-of-being/&quot;&gt;FULLNESS of BEING&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//oliver-bendorf/&quot;&gt;Oliver Baez Bendorf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//cheers/&quot;&gt;Cheers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//someone-quiet-down-the-biodiverse/&quot;&gt;Someone Quiet Down The Biodiverse “I”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/section&gt;</content><author><name>Timothy Morton</name></author><category term="20191111" /><summary type="html">Public lecture delivered April, 2019, to culminate the first ECOPOESIS gathering at California College of the Arts, San Francisco “The idea that alienation is being cut off from the future, the possibility that things might be different, has become very easy to think, and very good to think. All this has some consequences for art.” “Most ecological and plenty of non-ecological theories of alienation exist. Most of them state that we are alienated from a past where things were better, or perfect. But this is just the notion of the Fall, translated into some other mode, and that narrative is one way in which agricultural societies talk about the damage they have already done. The inherent speciesism (“nature” versus human culture) of this model is historically bankrolled by racism and patriarchy. There’s another way of thinking about alienation, logically, and luckily there are ways of showing that it’s true: if we aren’t alienated from the past we are alienated from the future. The media tell us that we are approaching the end of the world, because of global warming, but it’s much more serious than that. We are approaching us being dead and children now growing up and having to live in this biosphere, for a long time—longer than the end of time, in any case. The idea that alienation is being cut off from the future, the possibility that things might be different, has become very easy to think, and very good to think. All this has some consequences for art. What happens to a dream deferred? Does it dry up like a raisin in the sun? Or fester like a sore— And then run? Does it stink like rotten meat? Or crust and sugar over— like a syrupy sweet? Maybe it just sags like a heavy load. Or does it explode? This is a poem called “Harlem” and it’s by Langston Hughes. Let’s start to read it. Okay, well who wrote this poem? Langston Hughes would be the easiest answer. But all kinds of author functions, as Foucault used to say, exist. Maybe it’s better to say “Who or what wrote the poem?” It’s quite common for example to reduce Marxist criticism to its vulgar version, where you square the poem with the economic conditions of the day, say about a decade, in the country in which it was written. That Tennyson poem is a typical product of 1840s industrial capitalism in Britain. This Hughes poem is a typical product of 1950s American capitalism. Or whatever. So who wrote the poem? A human being? The human being’s family or psychic issues? The human being’s unconscious? The culture the human lived in? How many do we include? Who wrote the poem? Capitalism? The human genome? The biosphere? The ecosystem around the human poet? A light fall of rain one morning? The climate? The nuclear industry? The military industrial complex? The structure of racism in mid-twentieth century America? The struggle of African Americans to achieve basic rights? You see the thing is, ecological awareness is all about beginning to realize that things are happening on all kinds of scales, all at once, and that these scales aren’t like how you encounter them in museums or online. You can’t toggle nicely and smoothly back and forth from the very small to the very large, from the micro to the macro. That micro macro talk is Neoplatonic medieval something or other anyway. All right, let’s try something else. When was the poem written? The early twentieth century? The week Hughes put pen to paper? The month? One year in his life? The time of modernity? The time of modernism? The time of post-Neolithic civilization? The time of humans on Earth? In a way the poem was written in all of these times. Right? Just like in a way, all the beings I listed earlier wrote the poem. Let’s think about another aspect of the poem. Let’s think about the physical media of which it’s composed. Paper, typewriter ink; pixels, glass screens; microfilm. Roman Jakobson has a clunky but interesting six-part model of communication, that is useful in the way that all structuralist interpretative devices are useful, which is the way in which magic mixers that can slice and dice your food five different ways are useful. Put the poem through the blender, you learn something from what the blender does to it. So the first thing you notice is, there are these spacious gaps between some of the lines, while some other lines are close together. The first line, “What happens to a dream deferred?” has a lot of space around it—it’s trying to make you think, but it’s also trying to make you feel something, the opaque weight of all that deferment. It’s a tight little poem, whose lines have two or three rhythmical feet, and that means that unlike a wall of words, the space around the poem and between the stanzas is highlighted and becomes part of how you read it—you have to find some way to pronounce the blankness at the end of each line. In a way the poem a little bit lonely, like discarded little carton of orange juice that you find one day lying in an empty parking lot—not enough people are noticing what it’s saying. Or, conversely, the poem is trapped in a bath of blankness, pressing in on all sides—if you think about the parking lot the same way, it’s the same thing. something huge and constructed and blank yet weirdly invisible because it’s so hard to see presses in on our powers of thought and our physical powers on all sides. Your feet ache and you feel lonely and you regret the absence of butterflies. (The poem isn’t going to tell you. Poems let themselves be opaque altogether, like that parking lot, or we let them, or both. That means that poems are a place where what I like to call the future future gathers—the radical freshness that enables the possibility that things might be different, rather than the one we can build out from where we are now, using prediction and extrapolation. Again, my point is that we are alienated from the future, not from the past. we aren’t trying to recover an Edenic meaning that the poet somehow hid in there like a message in a bottle. We’re trying to assess the scope and awesomeness of this particular futural gateway.) The weight of deferment—the weight of waiting, as a matter of fact—is legible in the way the poem organizes the medium in which it has been inscribed—the so called “space” is actually the obtruding presence of the physical medium in which the poem exists. Say it’s on paper, well in that case, there’s a lot of pulp, trees, water, sunlight, all the things that make trees that make paper, in that pause. It’s not nothing. It’s not silence, as John Cage would have said—silence is just the way socially determined sounds taper off and you get to hear something else. It’s something I love about the Laser Interferometry Gravitational Observatory, about two miles north west of New Orleans, which is sort of Houston’s sister city. Two laser beams at right angles. It’s a very simple and relatively cheap experiment, compared at any rate with CERN. It’s tens of millions rather than billions, and there’s a difference, although it may seem absurdly expensive to us. At LIGO, these two lasers are bouncing off carefully calibrated mirrors. They pick up everything. Everything. Like cattle walking over the cattle grid in the field outside. People having arguments in an adjoining room about the experiment. Cars going past on the road outside. And you know what’s most uncanny is, if you know the waveforms for these things, you can subtract them from the waveform that results from the vibrating lasers. The movement of tectonic plates; the sound of aircraft…the lasers pick up everything, and when you cut out those cows walking over the grid and so on (I love the cows part), and there’s a tiny squiggle of something left, that you can’t explain, and it has the right sort of anticipated shape, do you know what is? That thing is a gravity wave. It’s a signature of two black holes colliding, one thousand light years away, a tiny flicker of spacetime in which everything on Earth got a little bit smaller and a little bit slower-living, then a little bit bigger and a little bit faster, then back to normal. Half an hour after the new improved LIGO was switched on, with more carefully calibrated lasers, two black holes collided and the energy equaled the output of the entire universe. And a ripple in spacetime spread out until it passed through everything on Earth. Is it not uncanny—rather like the idea of shadowtime that I was hearing about yesterday evening—that the gravity wave was right there, inside the waveform determined by moocows, cars, people arguing, tectonic plates… Does [the dream deferred] stink like rotten meat? Or crust and sugar over— like a syrupy sweet? Maybe it just sags like a heavy load. Or does it explode? Then you realize that the shadowtime is also in the imagery. The rotting of meat—the way it becomes inedible for humans because it’s being eaten by bacteria—the rotting is commensurate, in a metaphorical sense, with the deferment of the dream of un-alienated fullness of being, the “dream” that Hughes is talking about. It’s an ecological process—the appropriation of something we thought was just for us (it’s called “meat” not “cows” or “pigs” for this reason), by something else. The something else-ness is what makes the rottenness of the meat disgusting. That’s a thing that can happen in a few days in your kitchen; the racism is a thing that can happen for several hundred years in the hemisphere you live in on Earth. Metaphor is bringing these two timescales close without collapsing them into one another. “This is that,” in the realm of metaphor rather than math, means also that “this is not that.” Rotting time is not the same as dream deferment time. Then there’s the “crust”-ing and the “sugar”-ing over. Perhaps Hughes means that the dream becomes a candified, plastic, purely aesthetic version of itself, easy to understand but impossible to act out, because it’s been reduced to a commodified consumer object. Given the long history of slavery and sugar, this is a potent image indeed. The Romantic poets Coleridge and Southey argued for boycotting sugar in the mid 1790s, arguing that sugar was an extreme metaphor or catachresis: sugar is the crystallized blood of slaves. The implication in the image is that the sugar coating would be a symptom of continuing slavery. If sugar is alienated slave labor, a sugar-coated dream is an alienated one that you can’t realize, only appreciate. The sick part of the sugaring is that the dream might do it to itself, like how chocolate starts to separate and the ingredients rise and sink, something we call chocolate bloom. The sweetness of the dream might rise to the surface, encrust it and make it impossible to live it. The oppressive forces are installed inside of the dream, because the dream is in relation to them, and is born within them. And in an ecological context, if, as I believe, destroying racism would be tantamount to undoing a gigantic amount of the ideologies that sever us from other lifeforms, a severing actively and automatically pursued for thousands of years in what is called civilization, the response to the mid global warming of the Holocene—if destroying racism means that, then “Harlem” is talking obliquely about an ecological politics. Let’s talk about that for a moment—what I mean by that. Economics isn’t about dollars and interest rates. Dollars and interest rates aren’t about dollars and interest rates. All that stuff is reified capitalist theology, aka economics 101 in non-communist universities. Economics is how you organize your enjoyment, how you organize how stuff flows around in your house, your home, your world, all the shit that you have going on. And ecology is how the house, the home, the world that you’ve got going works, the logic of it. Economics and ecology are intertwined, etymologically, logically, socially, everything. So the question is, do these things pertain only to human beings? Do you have cockroaches and rats in or around your home? Do you look after a cat, and is it your house the cat lives in? Since I leave the house a lot more than the cat, in many ways it’s the cat’s house more than mine. This is sort of related to how, when I became a dad, I had that this is not my beautiful house feeling, very quickly, as Claire began to make it very clear that it was her house, not mine—psychologically that’s very true, isn’t it, your parents’ house that you grew up in was much more yours than theirs, it was the first world you lived in. They just happened to rent or buy or whatever another living space in a series. And related to this question, another question of pleasure. If we don’t like the theology of dollars and structural unemployment and having to work to live and all that stuff—if we think we are a bit socialist or Marxist or anarcho-communist whatever—do we think it would be a good idea to include cockroaches and cats in the revolutionary projects we have going on to transmogrify our homes, our worlds, into things that are more pleasurable for the beings who have stuff going on, like trying to find out where the rats really live in my cat’s case, or trying to write a lecture when you’re feeling really depressed about ecological politics and mass extinction in my case, etc? From a utilitarian point of view—which I find deeply problematic but whatever let’s use it, because it’s pretty default in our world—just existing is a form of pleasure. So if there are more revolutionary beings, like hedgehogs with little Che Guevara caps and stuff, that means more pleasure, so involving more lifeforms in revolutionary struggles would be better. Thanks very much for listening, my name is Tim Morton and if you have any questions I’ll be available afterwards. Right. So let’s go back to the poem. There’s the stuff about the dream rotting or glazing itself with sugar. I like very much how the dream immediately is a physical thing, something lying around in the sun. Then there’s another gap, and the idea that the dream might just continue, in an abject sort of way, “sagging” “Like a heavy load”—the dream itself has lost its utopian dreamlike lightness and has itself become one of the things that hangs over your head. In writing this poem, the authors (for Langston Hughes is one of them, but there are many that his work brings into alignment) seem to be observing that a whole complex range of timescales and histories are felt in the deferment of the dream, whose lingering potency is present in its absence in the way the poem organizes the blank space around it. But the blank space isn’t blank. The poem obviously plays with topics such as rotting and producing sugars, or being coated by sugars, processes that are to do with the biochemistry of lifeforms in a biosphere. The gaps in the poem mean that something there, but what is there? The open question quality is legible in the opacity of those gaps. What is there quite literally is the paper or the pixels, and what is there definitely and more figuratively is the labor of black people—what Karl Marx would call the species being of humans. Marx identifies this with imaginative projection and appropriation, but we don’t have to. Let’s just focus on the brute, aka silent, presence of physical being in those gaps, a physical being whose analog are the concrete images of rotting, sugaring and exploding. What is this physical being? The work of slaves, thought in typical western philosophy as a machinic functioning, like the behavior of an algorithm. Slavery articulates the anthropocentric differences between humans and so-called animals: humans, like slave owners, act, while animals, like slaves, merely behave. You can see immediately that the ways we have of talking about this stuff are deeply contaminated by speciesism, and that this has to do with racism, and I’m going to try to sort out exactly how in this talk. Because blank space isn’t just blank, and because the physical medium the poem appears in doesn’t just function smoothly in the background. That’s the whole point—the obtrusion of the paper or pixels into the poem itself is a kind of malfunction, like rotting or sugaring or sagging, and perhaps like exploding: that’s the question the poem poses altogether—is the exploding an error? We know it’s the logical consequence, within the poem, of continuing oppression. But does “explode” mean “explode into life and therefore become dangerous to the white powers that be” or does “explode” mean “evaporate as if it had never existed at all”? The blank space is and isn’t the poem. It’s a place where the poem malfunctions or rather, a place where the poem reveals that one being’s functioning is another being’s malfunction, and more deeply, how lines of poetry and spaces between them and everything else are all a series of malfunctions, such that smoothness is an illusion. Indeed, the deferment and the supposed silence are symptoms of a massive malfunction, in the fully “evil” sense of “mal” as the first syllables of that word. An evil functioning is what is detected in the gaps in the poem, the persistence of a state that has indeed been naturalized—the relations between white and black people—but which is anything but natural; or rather, the smoothness of its supposed naturalness is in fact a symptom of horrific violence, like the peaceful atmosphere after a tornado or bomb test. And isn’t that ecological awareness in a nutshell, really? The fact that since there is always an environment—some kind of opacity, some kind of surrounding something in which things are taking place—that the silence and absence isn’t to do with the reader being stupid or evil. Environmental awareness isn’t about being smarter or wiser than the average person. It’s just how awareness in general is, that it always takes place against some kind of taken for granted structure or background or set of assumptions or rows of beehives or vineyards or sugar plantations…there’s always a shadow side, always a shadowtime—it’s not that if you’re truly ecological there are no shadows. It’s that there are more. You are more haunted than you were. Ecological awareness most certainly is not about seeing things more clearly than Joe Public. Ecological awareness is about being willing to be haunted. We’ll see quite soon just how hard wired into ecology are concepts of specters, ghosts, shadows, fleeting things that appear in the corner of your eye. Ecologica awareness doesn’t mean you exorcised the bad artificial stuff and got back to nature. It mean that a greater number than ever of opaque semi-silent shadowy beings are making soft noises in the margins...it’s something that is powerfully conveyed in Amiri Baraka’s “Something in the Way of Things,” a poem whose paranoid tone aims to delineate the spooky, spectral presence of brutality and exploitation and racism in the fabric of the seemingly quiet street along which the narrator is walking. Paranoia is the default, ground state version of empathy—the more paranoid I am about you, are you really a robot or not, is the way I become more and more interested in you as a person. This whole idea that people are beings who obviously act and animals are beings who obviously behave, like robots, is theological and extreme, and, as I’m already starting to argue if you can feel it, racist. Ecological awareness is not about making other people feel stupid. It’s about realizing that because there’s at least one shadowy corner around which you’re not seeing, you yourself are always stupid. The shadows are infinite because we don’t know in advance how many there are, not because they go on forever. It’s all shadows. The dreams of dead people, waiting to be fulfilled by the living. All the entities that the poem gathers—African American humans, white people, cows and sheep and paper and pixels, all these beings coexist in ways that overlap. You could say for example that the human species is a heap of things such as humans and cows and computers and ideas about knitting and feudal monarchy and sand. And beaches are a heap of things such as sand and humans and waves and seaweed and so on. If you think of the world in terms of hyperobjects you are thinking of the world in terms of lots of gigantic overlapping things that are finite and fuzzy. Who wrote the poem is a heap of inconsistent things. When the poem was written is a heap of inconsistent times. And if you like ecological beings such as meadows and beaches and nice city streets with people being decent together, you had better believe in heaps. Logic, traditional vanilla Western logic that is, makes it almost impossible to believe in heaps. You can take bits out of a heap while still calling it a heap, until there’s nothing left, whereupon you realize that there must be no such things as heaps because look, here’s a whole lot of nothing and you were assuming there was a heap right up to that point. It’s called the Sorites paradox. Clouds, according to this, don’t really exist, because they’re made of little bits of cloud stuff; when you subtract the cloud stuff you get smaller and smaller bits of cloud stuff until there’s nothing—so there are no clouds, because clouds are vague. In the same way, you can argue that the Amazon jungle is just a gigantic feedlot waiting to happen, because if you take trees away there’s still a jungle, and you can keep on going till there’s just one tree, so jungles don’t really exist. But perhaps being vague is a criterion for existing. It certainly doesn’t seem easy to get rid of vague and downright contradictory things, without tying yourself in knots. Furthermore, you have to be a holist of some kind to be ecological. The trouble is, most forms of holism are exclusive and explosive. What do I mean? I mean that maybe we need to think that wholes are vague and messy and contradictory, not like Pan Man beings that eat up their contents and digest them totally. A cow could be part of one hyperobject—the human species thought in a non-essentialist way—and part of another one—the cow species for example, which in an expanded way also includes grass. The last time western philosophy tried to talk about all of whatever we are at once it got it very wrong and said “white man” all the time, like scratch the surface of any human and you’ll find a white man underneath. But humans caused global warming, not dolphins. We had better have an idea of who we are that is real and up to date and not racist or patriarchal. Thinking of ourselves as part of a vague heap of things that aren’t all to do with us exclusively, whoever we think we are, is a good place to start. There really are wholes, but they’re not your grandaddy’s whole, all perfect and fully integrated. Otherwise the whole called human is a totally different world from the world called moocows, and so we might get to thinking that we can do what we want with moocows or just totally ignore them. If we can’t overlap, we can’t communicate. If the concept of word means something self-contained and rigid, there’s no hope at all. And someone can say “My concept of world is much richer than yours, or you don’t have one at all, so I own Australia now.” I reckon this vacuum sealed world concept comes from rigid class hierarchies and I reckon that comes from demarcating the difference between human and nonhuman space using things like walls, because you have created granaries to preserve food from the ravages of mild global warming. You sealed off your human survival temporality, so you justify this by getting to think in various ways that the seal demarcates something real (religion, tragedy, philosophy, however you do it). It’s about 10 000 BCE, and you’re doing the right thing, at your scale, just like how starting your car in the morning doesn’t cause global warming. No, it really doesn’t. you’re not guilty. Besides, eating a bit less meat is much, much more effective than buying a Tesla, and easier too. You justify the demarcations and divisions of labor by explaining that the other classes must be different, really, really different beings altogether. And this is how racism begins to function. And it’s that internal human division that enables speciesism, the imagined difference between humans and everyone else. Think of that great diagram in robotics design, the Uncanny Valley. It explains racism while being racist in itself, so it’s very good to analyze, so we can come up with something else. On one side of the valley is a very suspicious being, the so-called “healthy human being,” and I think we can all hear the normal vs pathological, eugenics resonance in that concept. Exactly what is that, I don’t wonder for more than a second, speaking as we are close to Sacramento where in the early twentieth century horrible eugenics experiments were carried out, such as leaving newborn babies to die in hospital because they were unfit. On the other side of the valley is a cute so-called animal, or their electornic equivalent, the cute droid such as R2D2. They’re cute because they’re different—they’re separated by a thin hard line, which is what the Uncanny Valley looks like when you look across it at R2D2, because of foreshortening. Hitler was fond of his dog Blondi because Blondi was different enough from him, so that he could feel all those nice sublimated cute aggression feelings and make animal rights legislation. Let’s just face it—a lot of environmental organizations have had deep connections with white supremacy, and I’m explaining why. The Uncanny Valley diagram was created because it became well known in robotics that as you came closer and closer to imitating a lifelike human being, the robot passed through a phase that appeared strange or scary or creepy. The ultimate nadir of the Uncanny Valley is the zombie, the animated corpse who is a parody of the Cartesian self, just a body animated by some invisible force, moving in an automated way like the brooms in the Sorcerer’s Apprentice. According to hicks I overheard in rural Colorado (!), the zombie apocalypse is a pretty obviously racist concept about hordes of nonwhite people coming for your property, Barbara, and what’s awesome about many zombie works of art is how they subvert that. Anyway, the nice cute difference between me and R2D2 or Blondi the Alsatian is enabled by all the beings labeled as inhuman, subhuman and so on, beings that racism has chucked into the Uncanny Valley. Speciesism—the rigid difference between a human and a nonhuman—is enabled by racism—the machinery that categorizes some beings as inhuman or subhuman. Until you find out that you are in fact Neanderthals in some way, you tell yourself that they are uncanny failed versions of humans who just behaved like zombies, unlike us who have imagination and can see round corners and figure out how to make the zombies go extinct by slaughtering them all. So the way out of the Valley is actually not to get rid of the uncanny, which would make everything into a cute little machine coexisting in some fascist medium, we are all Earthlings or whatever, but actually the way out is to jump into the Valley, to realize that we ourselves are uncanny beings, that being a lifeform at all is being uncanny, because you are strangely strange all the way down. Because you are a symbiotic product of a truly random series of mutations called evolution. Which means that there is no Valley, because there is no healthy human being or perfect cute R2D2. Ecological awareness is like realizing you are on a gigantic flat plain on which exist all kinds of hazy weird beings whose status as alive or not alive, sentient or not sentient, conscious or not conscious (and even existing or not-existing) is not settled, but disturbed at every point. Again, ecological awareness doesn’t mean you stuck your head in a tree and forgot all your problems. It means you allowed yourself to be more haunted than ever, and in particular, that founding religious difference between act and behave that gives you humans versus everything else, imagination versus computing, let there be light versus being a slave, and all that toxic stuff, that act/behave boundary is not erased so that everything is a machine (which means there is still a perfume of act versus behave going on somewhere), but that everything is profoundly ambiguous. You can’t tell whether I am an android or not, and that’s what makes you treat me like a person. You don’t have to prove that rocks are definitely alive, you just have to notice that “alive” or “conscious” means I’m paranoid that you might be a zombie. Coexisting in symbiosis means you might have swallowed poison, and you did—it’s called being alive, which kills you in the end. There was no true difference between you and the cats and the vultures. The difference was enabled by difference between yourself and other humans. So what is the basic tone of a reality in which being haunted is the basic background to everything? This is the same as the reality in which the possibility that you might have poisoned yourself by eating that berry happens. The wondering whether you have been poisoned is the internal version of wondering what is around that corner. What do we call that tone? Well, it’s great, because we name it after the Greek for everything. We call it Panic. The Great God Pan and the Pan quality, which we call panic. Panic then really means everythingness, the realization that everything is happening. But everything-feel isn’t a lovely total thing. Everything means that there are so many incommensurate levels, so many shadows, so many specters. I like the word panic here because it also suggests a kind of quivering movement. Panic isn’t static—it tends to rush around or at least shiver on its own somewhere. We are beginning to notice that true fullness in the end is movement, always expanding, expansiveness…fullness of being isn’t some static thing to be achieved, but a dynamic process. Marx says it’s really like how production is actually the same as consumption, which by the way is the best way to start thinking about Marxist readings of poems, not as reflections of the freakin economy in which they were supposedly written. Plucking an apricot and putting it to your nose so you can smell that rose scent just after it’s fallen off a tree, then putting it in your mouth, chewing, swallowing…all that stuff is production. If that doesn’t speak volumes about the ways “act” and “behave” or “suffer” or “experience” have been violently severed and with violent consequences, I don’t know what would. Even in Marx—sorry to the Hegelian Marxist in Langston Hughes—produce doesn’t mean “let there be light” or pulling a rabbit out of a hat. It means something much more like “appreciate” or even “consume.” In one letter, Marx says that humans begin by production, “that is,” he says immediately, “by eating and drinking.” To eat or drink something you have to go along with it. If you’re a single celled organism, you have to envelop it…gulp! OMG did I just swallow poison? Again, this is the default phenomenology of symbiosis, a radical hospitality, giving rise to the possibility that the guest we let in might destroy us. To sag is to sink or subside gradually…think about how all the stuff that might happen to the dream has a really different temporality to it. Rotting is what happens to a corpse and one can’t help but visualize the history of lynching and the song “Strange Fruit.” Becoming glazed with sugar might take longer than rotting, if we were thinking about an item of food. Sagging has to do with just persisting but without being used by us. And exploding might be the sudden catastrophe that results when sagging has gone on for a while, or glazing, or rotting. (**) What we are experiencing in this poem is discarded, unutilized pleasure. What is wrong with society, according to this logic, is not that there is too much pleasure in capitalism or consumerism. It’s that there’s not enough. Look—you just chucked that carton of juice away and you hadn’t even finished it. Now we have to get in the car and go to the water park, and you’ll be thirsty. It’s hard perhaps to deal with, in an ecology talk, in a country whose growth in the nineteenth century was a way to enact the fantasies of working class European immigrants, so that when you walk down Main Street, you are walking inside their heads—the heads that imagine what those rich posh people must be eating while you’re starving on potatoes: all the meat and white bread they must be eating, eventually turned into easy to handle hamburgers, the Land of Cockaygne “All you can eat,” big gulp fantasy that has done a great job so far of almost destroying Earth, America, the biggest pile of Europe ever—a place where by the side of the road you might find a gigantic shoe not made by Claes Oldenburg but by some local guy, the biggest this, the most amount of that, eventually requiring feedlots and planet death. It’s hard to swallow for us eco people, brought up on the necessity—and let’s face it the stylistic distinction—of being abstemious. It’s hard to swallow that what ecological politics might be about is more pleasure and not less, and that thus in consumerism there is a distorted not fully nice version of the kind of pleasure we might expect if, say, keeping polar bears or coral alive was higher up on our agenda. But that’s exactly the imagery in this poem—if you don’t try to enact it, the dream could rot or bloom with sugar or sag and explode, scattering its possibilities and causing unintended damage—and I suggest that since it’s a key, major part of the poetics of anti-racism and the struggle of African American people, and since this struggle is key to an ecological politics, we shouldn’t ignore that imagery. The poem is talking about interpretation, in lots of ways. The dream deferred is, as I pointed out earlier, the full meaning of the poem, which haunts the sentences like a shadow from the future. Dreams are like that, says Freud: they are infinitely interpretable. But what does infinity mean? If you try to count up to it, you won’t be able to, so the idea that it means “going on and on forever” is a dangerous illusion, an ideological one I would argue. Infinity means you can’t count it. There might be three of whatever it is, but you can’t know that in advance. There might be twenty million, but a thing stops somewhere. Interpretation stops somewhere. Alan Turing had to invent the idea of computers to prove that things stop somewhere. You can’t make a program powerful enough to predict when every other program will go into an infinite loop. Turing was trying to prove Gödel’s Incompleteness Theorem. A logical system must be flawed in order to exist so you can make it go into an infinite loop. And you can’t design an uber meta program that can predict (aka the future…) when any other algorithm will go into an infinite loop…which means that the future is open, like how poems are, because there must always be some opacity in a logical system in order for it to be transparent, or true. Godel created his theorem because about Russell and Whitehead were trying to police mathematician Cantor (a mathematician like Godel), police him with logic. Cantor discovered infinities that were ‘bigger” than regular. And infinity truly means you can’t count (compute) it, not it goes on forever…in between Hilbert was wondering whether computational processes could be seen to stop (the Entscheidungsproblem)…it’s like they invented computers to prove that computers can’t do everything…and then the Max 8 showed up… And in parallel this war between logic and math halfway through the twentieth century, like “Harlem,” like the Golden Spike in global warming data that scientists point to in 1945, this war between logic and math is about Tarski inventing the idea of metalanguage to police sentences like “this sentence is false”—you can always invent a sentence that will blow up the rule…like how Lacan says there is no metalanguage… The infinite openness of futurality is what the essence of a thing is, as opposed to its appearance, which is if you think about it the past. Automated systems such as economies or programs that make planes crash are past states of thought and feeling encoded in rules, customs, habits, lines of code. The trouble with automation is not artificial intelligence—heaven knows I may be an android. The trouble with automation is that the past is eating the future. Automation, if the past sucked, and generally it does, can you tell?—means alienation. Openness and finitude thus go together. Another way of saying what the mathematicians are saying against the western logicians, is that there’s at least one level on which you or your interpretation or your action, whatever it may be, suck(s). Some lifeform you didn’t think about gets killed or eventually you get cancer because you ate too many of whatever in whatever particular way. Ecological awareness, meaning you realize things happen on lots of space and time scales at once, means knowing that at some point at least you are a hypocrite. You can’t get it perfect. Not knowing when an entity wil come to an end is thus part of panic, the basic ecological mood, the great god Pan. You that a thing is flawed, that it will stop, but you can’t know exactly when or how, at least not for everything. Will mass extinction wipe us out, and when? It’s like that. It’s a good time to panic and think and do something about it. Sugar is a thing that evokes both Nature and culture, civilization and barbarism, pleasure and slavery. And in Hughes’s poem, a sugary death is only one way of thinking about the dream. The poem explodes the difference between coating a thing with sugar and letting that thing glaze itself—culture and nature. Nature and culture both now explode in the face of ecological awareness, evaporating in the face of what I like to call the symbiotic real—the fact of being in a biosphere where exorbitant and always risky mutual aid is in effect everywhere. The blankness of the page is the automated zombie apocalypse—it’s whiteness eating your brain with memes, stopping you from thinking, obtruding on the dream like a huge hot parking lot surrounding a carton of orange juice. Sagging suggests just letting gravity, aka spacetime, do its thing, a kind of existing in indifference. It’s not about stasis--it’s moving. Sagging is an abject movement that could indeed explode from the inside as slime as much as fire, like ectoplasm, the spectral body fluid; sagging is about physical being and time, “going out of shape” and getting old…Environmental creepiness is there in that racist southern gothic mood, half detected in “Harlem” and fully there in “Strange Fruit,” the weight of the past sagging or weighing like a nightmare. The futurality of things (the dream deferred) could sag in the toxic atmosphere of automation…the plane that can’t crash, the ship that can’t sink—didn’t we learn anything from the Titanic or from Titanic? Leonardo di Caprio would be pulped in a malfunctioning Max 8, that massively distributed Titanic. You can’t even make a romantic film about it. Is that progress? 2018 | 2019 | People | About Timothy Morton FULLNESS of BEING Oliver Baez Bendorf Cheers Someone Quiet Down The Biodiverse “I”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Cheers</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/cheers/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cheers" /><published>2019-11-01T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-11-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/cheers</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/cheers/">&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 2;&quot;&gt;
Tonight we think of you, golden toad— no longer with us on this plane, last seen 15 May 1989 in
&lt;br /&gt;
cloud forest and not a single one of you since. Decomposed? You lived underground, you
&lt;br /&gt;
came
&lt;br /&gt;
up once a year to to mate— in piggybacks and puddles. Smooth orange skin, halfway
&lt;br /&gt;
translucent. Sunny D poured into a mold. Indiscriminate acts to hurtle your species into the future.
&lt;br /&gt;
Possible
&lt;br /&gt;
to foil this extinction through propagation? No, the population’s the problem. Too many humans. 
&lt;br /&gt;
Still
&lt;br /&gt;
not likely to go quietly— Brenda says it’s &lt;i&gt;relaxation time&lt;/i&gt;— but not like that, not long now.
&lt;br /&gt;
Be
&lt;br /&gt;
the carbon and the green. No one there to identify their bones at the scene. Just no one there at all 
&lt;br /&gt;
except
&lt;br /&gt;
sun, moon, woolly mammoth, and the moon’s moons, and probably roaches, rats, pigeons, and squirrels.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

Burrowing was supposed to be in one’s favor— unlike huddling together on land— but it comes for 
&lt;br /&gt;
us all. Huddled together at the gay bar, parade, campus, theater, potluck, funeral.
&lt;br /&gt;
Oop
&lt;br /&gt;
Making it about them again. Golden toad last known mating episode 1987 year I was born
&lt;br /&gt;
Oop
&lt;br /&gt;
Golden toad
&lt;br /&gt;
Golden toad
&lt;br /&gt;
Thank you for returning your infinite matter to the biosphere.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- End of page --&gt;
&lt;!-- Start of Bottom Footer --&gt;

&lt;nav class=&quot;nav justify-content-center&quot; style=&quot;box-shadow: 0 2px 2px -2px rgba(0,0,0,0);&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;nav-container&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;//&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h2 class=&quot;nav-title&quot;&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul style=&quot;position: relative&quot;&gt;
      &lt;!-- &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;//&quot;&gt;Issue&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; --&gt;
      &lt;li class=&quot;nav-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;nav-link&quot; href=&quot;//2018-fall&quot;&gt;2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li class=&quot;nav-item&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;|&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li class=&quot;nav-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;nav-link&quot; href=&quot;//2019-fall&quot;&gt;2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li class=&quot;nav-item&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;|&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li class=&quot;nav-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;nav-link&quot; href=&quot;//people&quot;&gt;People&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li class=&quot;nav-item&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;|&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li class=&quot;nav-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;nav-link&quot; href=&quot;//about&quot;&gt;About&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/nav&gt;

&lt;section id=&quot;sec4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//timothy-morton/&quot;&gt;Timothy Morton&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//fullness-of-being/&quot;&gt;FULLNESS of BEING&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//oliver-bendorf/&quot;&gt;Oliver Baez Bendorf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//cheers/&quot;&gt;Cheers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//someone-quiet-down-the-biodiverse/&quot;&gt;Someone Quiet Down The Biodiverse “I”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/section&gt;</content><author><name>Oliver Baez Bendorf</name></author><category term="20191111" /><summary type="html">Tonight we think of you, golden toad— no longer with us on this plane, last seen 15 May 1989 in cloud forest and not a single one of you since. Decomposed? You lived underground, you came up once a year to to mate— in piggybacks and puddles. Smooth orange skin, halfway translucent. Sunny D poured into a mold. Indiscriminate acts to hurtle your species into the future. Possible to foil this extinction through propagation? No, the population’s the problem. Too many humans. Still not likely to go quietly— Brenda says it’s relaxation time— but not like that, not long now. Be the carbon and the green. No one there to identify their bones at the scene. Just no one there at all except sun, moon, woolly mammoth, and the moon’s moons, and probably roaches, rats, pigeons, and squirrels. Burrowing was supposed to be in one’s favor— unlike huddling together on land— but it comes for us all. Huddled together at the gay bar, parade, campus, theater, potluck, funeral. Oop Making it about them again. Golden toad last known mating episode 1987 year I was born Oop Golden toad Golden toad Thank you for returning your infinite matter to the biosphere. 2018 | 2019 | People | About Timothy Morton FULLNESS of BEING Oliver Baez Bendorf Cheers Someone Quiet Down The Biodiverse “I”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Timothy Morton</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/timothy-morton/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Timothy Morton" /><published>2019-01-01T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-01-01T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/timothy-morton</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/timothy-morton/">&lt;p&gt;Rita Shea Guffey Chair in the Environmental Humanities
Rice University
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
In April 2019, the Architectural Ecologies Lab and the MFA Writing Program at California College of the Arts invited 48 guests to attend the first gathering of the ECOPOESIS Movement in San Francisco. Founded in 2018 by Christopher Falliers, Adam Marcus, and Leslie Carol Roberts, all CCA professors, the project explores ideas of how we talk about and message climate change – and more broadly ecologies. The goal was to generate collective, embodied messaging, which in turn would activate more conversations, and so on. Core to the project are “signal words,” all which begin with the letters “re-.” In April, the signal words were retreat, remain, resist, and the group was divided into three sections – with each taking one of the words for guidance. The guests were artists, writers, designers,journalists, graduate students, national park supervisors, academics from varied institutions, nonprofit administrators, selected for their varying lenses and expertise. Further focus was added by inviting Timothy Morton, author of Dark Ecologies and other ecological books, to serve as another reference point. An excerpt of Dark Ecologies was read by the group prior to the gathering. A cornerstone of ECOPOESIS is gathering at the table for food  and conversation in an informal setting. One-and-a-half days and four meals later, the group presented their work and wrapped up with this public talk by Morton, who generously offered to 11.11 the chance to publish his remarks.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Timothy Morton is Rita Shea Guffey Chair in English at Rice University. He has collaborated with Björk, Jennifer Walshe, Jeff Bridges, Olafur Eliasson, and Pharrell Williams. He co-wrote and appears in Living in the Future’s Past, a 2018 film about global warming with Jeff Bridges. He is the author of Being Ecological (Penguin, 2018), Humankind: Solidarity with Nonhuman People (Verso, 2017), Dark Ecology: For a Logic of Future Coexistence (Columbia, 2016), Nothing: Three Inquiries in Buddhism (Chicago, 2015), Hyperobjects: Philosophy and Ecology after the End of the World (Minnesota, 2013), Realist Magic: Objects, Ontology, Causality (Open Humanities, 2013), The Ecological Thought (Harvard, 2010), Ecology without Nature (Harvard, 2007), eight other books and 200 essays on philosophy, ecology, literature, music, art, architecture, design and food. His work has been translated into 10 languages. In 2014, Morton gave the Wellek Lectures in Theory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 style=&quot;padding: 5vh 0 1vh 0;&quot;&gt;Fall 2019 Issue&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;collection-list&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;//fullness-of-being/&quot;&gt;Fullness of Being&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="20181111" /><summary type="html">Rita Shea Guffey Chair in the Environmental Humanities Rice University In April 2019, the Architectural Ecologies Lab and the MFA Writing Program at California College of the Arts invited 48 guests to attend the first gathering of the ECOPOESIS Movement in San Francisco. Founded in 2018 by Christopher Falliers, Adam Marcus, and Leslie Carol Roberts, all CCA professors, the project explores ideas of how we talk about and message climate change – and more broadly ecologies. The goal was to generate collective, embodied messaging, which in turn would activate more conversations, and so on. Core to the project are “signal words,” all which begin with the letters “re-.” In April, the signal words were retreat, remain, resist, and the group was divided into three sections – with each taking one of the words for guidance. The guests were artists, writers, designers,journalists, graduate students, national park supervisors, academics from varied institutions, nonprofit administrators, selected for their varying lenses and expertise. Further focus was added by inviting Timothy Morton, author of Dark Ecologies and other ecological books, to serve as another reference point. An excerpt of Dark Ecologies was read by the group prior to the gathering. A cornerstone of ECOPOESIS is gathering at the table for food and conversation in an informal setting. One-and-a-half days and four meals later, the group presented their work and wrapped up with this public talk by Morton, who generously offered to 11.11 the chance to publish his remarks. Timothy Morton is Rita Shea Guffey Chair in English at Rice University. He has collaborated with Björk, Jennifer Walshe, Jeff Bridges, Olafur Eliasson, and Pharrell Williams. He co-wrote and appears in Living in the Future’s Past, a 2018 film about global warming with Jeff Bridges. He is the author of Being Ecological (Penguin, 2018), Humankind: Solidarity with Nonhuman People (Verso, 2017), Dark Ecology: For a Logic of Future Coexistence (Columbia, 2016), Nothing: Three Inquiries in Buddhism (Chicago, 2015), Hyperobjects: Philosophy and Ecology after the End of the World (Minnesota, 2013), Realist Magic: Objects, Ontology, Causality (Open Humanities, 2013), The Ecological Thought (Harvard, 2010), Ecology without Nature (Harvard, 2007), eight other books and 200 essays on philosophy, ecology, literature, music, art, architecture, design and food. His work has been translated into 10 languages. In 2014, Morton gave the Wellek Lectures in Theory. Fall 2019 Issue Fullness of Being</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/Timothy_Morton.jpeg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Oliver Baez Bendorf</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oliver-bendorf/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Oliver Baez Bendorf" /><published>2019-01-01T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-01-01T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oliver-bendorf</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oliver-bendorf/">&lt;p&gt;Oliver Baez Bendorf is a poet. He is the author of two collections, Advantages of Being Evergreen (CSU Poetry Center 2019), which Gabrielle Calvocoressi called “an essential book for our time and for all time,” and The Spectral Wilderness (Kent State U. 2015), selected by Mark Doty for the Stan &amp;amp; Tom Wick Poetry Prize. His poems can be found in recent and forthcoming issues of American Poetry Review, Poetry, BOMB, New England Review, and elsewhere, and were anthologized in Troubling the Line: Trans and Genderqueer Poetry and Poetics (Nightboat 2013). Oliver was born and raised in Iowa and he is currently an assistant professor of poetry at Kalamazoo College in Michigan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 style=&quot;padding: 5vh 0 1vh 0;&quot;&gt;Fall 2019 Issue&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;collection-list&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;//cheers/&quot;&gt;Cheers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;//someone-quiet-down-the-biodiverse/&quot;&gt;Someone Quiet Down The Biodiverse “I”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="20191111" /><summary type="html">Oliver Baez Bendorf is a poet. He is the author of two collections, Advantages of Being Evergreen (CSU Poetry Center 2019), which Gabrielle Calvocoressi called “an essential book for our time and for all time,” and The Spectral Wilderness (Kent State U. 2015), selected by Mark Doty for the Stan &amp;amp; Tom Wick Poetry Prize. His poems can be found in recent and forthcoming issues of American Poetry Review, Poetry, BOMB, New England Review, and elsewhere, and were anthologized in Troubling the Line: Trans and Genderqueer Poetry and Poetics (Nightboat 2013). Oliver was born and raised in Iowa and he is currently an assistant professor of poetry at Kalamazoo College in Michigan. Fall 2019 Issue Cheers Someone Quiet Down The Biodiverse “I”</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/oliver-baez-bendorf.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">White Rabbits</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/White-Rabbits/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="White Rabbits" /><published>2018-11-01T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-11-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/white-rabbits</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/White-Rabbits/">&lt;p sytle=&quot;line-height: 2;&quot;&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Ye-ye always had a pocketful of White Rabbit candies for me when I was a child.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The first time, I was three, maybe four. Ye-ye put a White Rabbit in the palm of his hand, then quickly closed both fists, shook both hands, and opened them. The candy was gone. Then he closed his fists and had me pick one.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I tapped a knuckle, and he smiled. He opened his hand and there lay the White Rabbit.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Who could resist? The white wrappers with the red and blue bands, the outline of the rabbit on the side. I untwisted the wrapper and found another piece of clear plastic around the white taffy, which I tried to peel off, but Ye-ye shook his head, and showed me how to put the candy on my tongue. Miracle of miracles, the &quot;plastic&quot; wrap began to melt. It was paper made from rice paste, and it dissolved like a communion wafer on my tongue, revealing the sweet taffy beneath. This was what love tasted like when I was three: like magic and sugar and pounded rice paste.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
My mother and father didn't want me to eat candy. They said candy would rot my teeth out. But eating White Rabbits was a religious experience for me now. There was no turning back.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Ye-ye didn't have any teeth. He wore dentures, which he put in a glass beside his bed at night to soak. I saw them floating in the glass free of his mouth when he spent the summers with us in our house in Southern California after my brother, Nathan, was born. Nai-nai had died that spring, and my parents thought Ye-ye would be lonely. I also think they knew he would be willing to look after me for free. My mother was tense and tired and everything I did made her upset. I thought that would eventually change after the baby grew up a little bit, after the crying stopped, or grew less frequent.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The moment I woke up, I would sit up in my bed and wait for Ye-ye to come, the second earliest riser. He'd peek into my room, and I'd hold up my arms, and he'd come and pull me out of bed.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Ye-ye took me for walks in the ancient stroller. The dew still glistened on the lawns, the air had a faint chill. He'd walk me to the corner and back, all by ourselves. We felt daring in the world.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
This arrangement continued for years. Ye-ye coming for the summer, my brother taking all my mother's energy.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Ye-ye and I only got lost once.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
By then I was six, and Nathan had an earache. It seemed to last the entire summer. He cried all the time. Mama was irritable. Everything I did made her tense. Same old.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We began as we always had. Ye-ye and I walked hand-in-hand up the shaded sidewalks before the sun had risen high enough to burn the dew off and scorch the air. Then we went a little farther than usual, all the way to the corner, and then across that street, and up the block to the big house with gray turrets and large dense fruit trees. The owners were an elderly white couple and they had pomegranates. I'd gone on a field trip for kindergarten and I remembered the way.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The nice couple had picked pomegranates from their trees and sliced them open and placed them on picnic tables covered with plastic red-and-white tablecloths. We'd all been given a quarter pomegranate to suck the seeds out of.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
It was morning and I was hungry, and who knew when my mother would get up and make breakfast anymore.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&quot;I know a good place to go,&quot; I told Ye-ye, and we set off.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
But when we got to the corner, I could see the house but it was nothing like the friendly welcoming home of my memory. The tall wrought-iron gates were not tied open with streamers; there were not lines of elementary school children on the lawn with paper plates in their hands. The house was dark, shadowed, the pomegranate trees overgrown, the shade dripping from the eaves and the leaf-laden branches menacing. Even the spiky turrets of the house, which had made it seem castle-like on the field trip, now appeared threatening, as though a witch not a princess might live inside.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I froze in place, Ye-ye's warm hand in mine.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
A bird cawed overhead. Some kind of jay. It flew into the tree, then seemed caught in the sticky darkness. Its cawing turned distressful, a shriek.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I squeezed Ye-ye's hand. He patted my head.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Ye-ye looked left and right. I knew he was wondering which way to go.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
At first I couldn't move, then all at once, I knew we needed to run.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I pulled Ye-ye's hand and we turned, crossed to the sunny side of the street. I knew there was another way home. A way only in the sunshine.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
There was a little girl, Karen, whose house I'd gone to for a birthday party. I could picture the house, white with blue shutters, and an orange tree in the lawn, a Big Wheel on the lawn. I felt certain we could reach it. I had walked to the house with Mama pushing Nathan's stroller.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We walked another block. Ye-ye followed me, patiently, trusting me.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The sun was moving higher in the sky, the shadows retreating, but I didn't feel safe yet from the inky shaded witchy house. We walked and walked. And then I was lost.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I knew we should turn. We turned and turned but what should have been our street, our house, our copse of avocado trees, was a different house, one with a chain-link fence and a large German Shepherd with nicked ears staring through the wire. The dog barked, his harsh voice like electric volts to my heart.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Ye-ye felt it, and gripped my hand too tightly, it hurt my fingers, and he pulled me along, but he couldn't walk very fast. Still he pulled me alongside him, and I didn't dare say Ouch, until we were out of range of the dog, a block and a turn away. We could hear the echo of his bark, but he was nowhere to be seen, and he surely couldn't see us either, I hoped.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We were truly lost then.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
There was an old white man on a lawn chair in front of one of the houses. He wore shorts and an undershirt and his belly poked out from his shorts. He held a limp hose in one hand. Water trickled from its mouth.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
There were patches of dirt on his lawn, and dandelions, the kind my father would not tolerate on ours. The moment a single one appeared, Papa would march out with his garden spade and his thick gloves and a plastic trash bag, and he'd dig the dandelion up, all the way to the root, and bag it, and tie the bag, and put it in the trash barrel before it could spread, he said. We were one of only a handful of Chinese families in our town in those days, and Papa felt it was important to show everyone that we understood the rules, that we knew how to keep our lawn nice, that we belonged.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The white man stared at us, and Ye-ye hesitated. I knew he was thinking we could ask the man for directions, but I didn't want to. I was afraid of the man. I prayed in my thoughts, Ye-ye, no, we can't stop here. Ever since I was very little, before I could talk, I knew if I thought hard enough, Ye-ye would hear me and understand.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
No, Ye-ye, I prayed. We can't stop.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Ye-ye understood, and we kept walking.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The sun was very high overhead, and it was hot. Ye-ye was wearing his long sleeved jacket, and he stopped and took it off, and folded it in half, and half again, and tucked it under his arm.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
He took my right hand again in his left. My hand was hot and sticky and sweaty, but still he held me tightly.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We walked until Ye-ye suddenly had to stop on some stranger's lawn. He led me to a large shade tree, and he leaned his hand against the trunk. He took out his white handkerchief and wiped his face, and neck, and then the top of his head.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We were standing on the grass, which white people would not like. I knew from experience when my best friend, Gabby Ocampo, and I ran across the mean neighbor's lawn next to Gabby's house, and the old white woman had run out and shouted, &quot;You brats get off my lawn!&quot;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Ye-ye sat down on the lawn and patted the grass so that I would sit next to him. I was afraid we were going to get in trouble; there were white people in the house, looking at us through a crack in the curtains of their front window. I saw them flickering there, the curtains rippling, back and forth. But I obeyed and sat on the grass.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Ye-ye reached into his jacket pocket and pulled out a handful of very melted White Rabbits.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Ye-ye's eyes twinkled as we both sucked on our candies, resisting the urge to chew, him because it was bad for his dentures, me out of solidarity. Except at the last minute when I absolutely couldn't stand it and I had to chomp on the candy until it was gone.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Then like magic, Papa and Mama drove by in our Buick. They were driving slowly, all the windows down, and I saw them, and jumped up and ran towards them.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Mama shouted, &quot;Ning-ning, don't run into the street!&quot;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
And I froze in place.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Papa parked the car right there in the middle of the street. He jumped out of the driver's side, and I thought, We are saved!
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Then he ran over to me, and swatted me on the ass, once, twice, three times. &quot;Bad girl!&quot; he said. And swatted me again.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I was too old for this. It wasn't the pain that made me grimace and fight back my tears as I stood there on the sidewalk in front of Ye-ye, in front of the white family who were watching from behind the curtains of their picture window. The indignity.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Papa dragged me by the arm to the car. He opened the back door and said, &quot;Get in!&quot; Then he pushed me inside and I sat down, even though the hot vinyl burned the back of my legs.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Then Papa went to get Ye-ye, and he helped him up slowly, and he took his arm, and walked him to the other side of the car.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Mama said, &quot;Poor Ye-ye. Oh, poor Ye-ye. He could have had a stroke in this heat.&quot; Nathan was on her lap and he started to whimper.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Ye-ye said something to Papa in Chinese that I couldn't understand and Papa said something in Chinese back, only very loudly, and over and over.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Then Mama said, &quot;Ning-ning, what were you thinking?&quot;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
That's how it was, ever since Nathan was born. I was blamed for everything that went wrong. His illness, his crying all the time, his having to go to the hospital, all the tests, all the doctors.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&quot;Ning-ning, I'm ashamed of you. You know you're not supposed to leave the house alone. What has gotten into you?&quot;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
And I thought like saying, But I wasn't alone. I was with Ye-ye. But I didn't say it. Which turned out to be a good thing, because the next thing Mama said was, &quot;You could have gotten Ye-ye killed. You're lucky we found you.&quot;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
And that's when I cried for real, tears and snot and shame, in front of everyone.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
After that, my parents became fearful. I wasn't allowed to go out by myself, and I wasn't allowed to go on walks with Ye-ye.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&quot;He's forgetful. He's not himself. You're too much for him.&quot;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The next year, Ye-ye didn't come for the summer at all. He stayed in his apartment in New York City with my uncle. In fact, he wouldn't visit again in person ever. Traveling had become too hard for him.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
However, he continued to send me White Rabbits in a box for my birthday and New Year's, along with a red envelope, every year until he died when I was eleven.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I didn't have White Rabbits again until I went to China on a study abroad trip my junior year of college.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In advance of Spring Festival, the street stalls were suddenly full of bins and bins of White Rabbit candies. Walking the streets around the campus of Nanjing University, I was thrilled to see the candy of my youth. I immediately bought a bag full and brought them back to the dorm.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I passed them around to everyone I met. &quot;I loved these when I was a child,&quot; I explained.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The old man who sat in the guardhouse at the gate politely took a handful but the women who worked in the building merely shook their heads and laughed uncomfortably.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
My Chinese roommate looked on in horror. &quot;My grandmother liked those,&quot; she said.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I knew I was a disappointment to her. This whole mixed-nationality roommate situation was an experiment on campus, a sign of China's emergence from decades of seclusion, and was supposed to be an honor. My roommate had signed up and gone through some kind of rigorous screening process. She had been promised an American, and she'd expected some chic, blonde white girl with exotic ways and instead she got me, a Chinese American with cheap taste.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Back in our room she pulled out a Toblerone roll from the drawer of her desk and popped a piece in her mouth to make her point.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
After that I kept my fetish to myself. But every morning when I woke, the loudspeaker outside our window blaring music for the morning exercises that my roommate and I refused to rise for, I reached from the cocoon of my comforter into the frosty air of our unheated dorm room, and pulled a new White Rabbit from the bag I kept on my desk. I untwisted the familiar white wrapper with the red and blue stripes and the rabbit outlined in blue on the side and popped the candy into my mouth. Pulling my comforter around me, I closed my eyes, as the sensuous layer of sweetened rice paper melted into the milky taffy.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I'd come to Nanjing hoping to find some connection to my past, something that would perhaps console me, make up for the losses, for the sense of something missing in me, the hole that was always there in my life in America. But I was no fool. I knew that my grandfather was dead and the China of his memories was gone too, and the Chinese who lived now were rapidly throwing off the past and embracing a future of their own creation. Nothing in China was quite what I'd expected or hoped for. But secretly savoring my White Rabbit each morning gave me courage and sugar and just enough nostalgia to ready myself to get out of bed and embrace the new day.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- End of page --&gt;
&lt;!-- Start of Bottom Footer --&gt;

&lt;nav class=&quot;nav justify-content-center&quot; style=&quot;box-shadow: 0 2px 2px -2px rgba(0,0,0,0);&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;nav-container&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;//&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h2 class=&quot;nav-title&quot;&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul style=&quot;position: relative&quot;&gt;
      &lt;!-- &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;//&quot;&gt;Issue&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; --&gt;
      &lt;li class=&quot;nav-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;nav-link&quot; href=&quot;//2018-fall&quot;&gt;2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li class=&quot;nav-item&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;|&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li class=&quot;nav-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;nav-link&quot; href=&quot;//2019-fall&quot;&gt;2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li class=&quot;nav-item&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;|&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li class=&quot;nav-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;nav-link&quot; href=&quot;//people&quot;&gt;People&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li class=&quot;nav-item&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;|&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li class=&quot;nav-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;nav-link&quot; href=&quot;//about&quot;&gt;About&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/nav&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;container&quot;&gt;

  &lt;section id=&quot;sec1&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//dodie-bellamy/&quot;&gt;Dodie Bellamy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//The-Violence-of-the-Image/&quot;&gt;The Violence of the Image&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Stuff-My-Stalker-Has-Ordered-for-Me-Online/&quot;&gt;Stuff My Stalker Has Ordered for Me Online&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//may-lee-chai/&quot;&gt;May-lee Chai&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//White-Rabbits/&quot;&gt;White Rabbits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//tongo-eisen-martin/&quot;&gt;Tongo Eisen-Martin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Fish-With-Ambition-to-Become-the-River/&quot;&gt;Fish With Ambition to Become the River&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Two-Nights-on-16th-Street/&quot;&gt;Two Nights on 16th Street&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Many-Does-To-Go-Or-Turns-The-Pen/&quot;&gt;Many Doses To Go Or Turns the Pen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//jennifer-firestone/&quot;&gt;Jennifer Firestone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Selections-from-Ten/&quot;&gt;Selections from Ten&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/section&gt;
  &lt;section id=&quot;sec2&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//sheila-heti/&quot;&gt;Sheila Heti&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Literature-Against-Anxiety/&quot;&gt;Literature Against Anxiety&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//lorelei-lee/&quot;&gt;Lorelei Lee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Leaving-San-Francisco/&quot;&gt;Leaving San Francisco&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//miranda-mellis/&quot;&gt;Miranda Mellis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//The-Imperceptible-Utopia/&quot;&gt;The Imperceptible Utopia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//To-Not-Become-a-Pillar-of-Salt/&quot;&gt;To Not Become a Pillar of Salt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//christopher-merrill/&quot;&gt;Christopher Merrill&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Rustams-Throne/&quot;&gt;Rustam's Throne&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/section&gt;
  &lt;section id=&quot;sec3&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//katherine-min/&quot;&gt;Katherine Min&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//On-Being-a-Sprinter/&quot;&gt;On Being a Sprinter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//On-Being-Humpty-Dumpty/&quot;&gt;On Being Humpty Dumpty&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//laura-mullen/&quot;&gt;Laura Mullen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Scream/&quot;&gt;Scream&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Elsie-Disclaimer/&quot;&gt;Elsie (Disclaimer)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Elsie-The-Coward/&quot;&gt;Elsie The Coward&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Elsie-Doesnt-Mind/&quot;&gt;Elsie Doesn't Mind&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//El-C-the-C/&quot;&gt;El C the C&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//The-Imaginary-Begins/&quot;&gt;The Imaginary Begins&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//C-Section/&quot;&gt;C Section&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Queen-of-Muses/&quot;&gt;Queen of Muses&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//ron-silliman/&quot;&gt;Ron Silliman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//from-Parrot-Eyes-Lust/&quot;&gt;from Parrot Eyes Lust&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//ross-simonini/&quot;&gt;Ross Simonini&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Interview-with-Paul-McCarthy/&quot;&gt;Legs Spread, Mask On:  Reflections on Snow White, Deleuze, and Late Capitalism&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/section&gt;
  &lt;section id=&quot;sec4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//john-yau/&quot;&gt;John Yau&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//The-Presidents-Second-Telegram/&quot;&gt;The President's Second Telegram&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//The-Presidents-Telegram-3/&quot;&gt;The President's Telegram (3)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//The-Congressmans-Explination/&quot;&gt;The Congressman's Explanation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/section&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>May-lee Chai</name></author><category term="20181111" /><summary type="html">Ye-ye always had a pocketful of White Rabbit candies for me when I was a child. The first time, I was three, maybe four. Ye-ye put a White Rabbit in the palm of his hand, then quickly closed both fists, shook both hands, and opened them. The candy was gone. Then he closed his fists and had me pick one. I tapped a knuckle, and he smiled. He opened his hand and there lay the White Rabbit. Who could resist? The white wrappers with the red and blue bands, the outline of the rabbit on the side. I untwisted the wrapper and found another piece of clear plastic around the white taffy, which I tried to peel off, but Ye-ye shook his head, and showed me how to put the candy on my tongue. Miracle of miracles, the &quot;plastic&quot; wrap began to melt. It was paper made from rice paste, and it dissolved like a communion wafer on my tongue, revealing the sweet taffy beneath. This was what love tasted like when I was three: like magic and sugar and pounded rice paste. My mother and father didn't want me to eat candy. They said candy would rot my teeth out. But eating White Rabbits was a religious experience for me now. There was no turning back. Ye-ye didn't have any teeth. He wore dentures, which he put in a glass beside his bed at night to soak. I saw them floating in the glass free of his mouth when he spent the summers with us in our house in Southern California after my brother, Nathan, was born. Nai-nai had died that spring, and my parents thought Ye-ye would be lonely. I also think they knew he would be willing to look after me for free. My mother was tense and tired and everything I did made her upset. I thought that would eventually change after the baby grew up a little bit, after the crying stopped, or grew less frequent. The moment I woke up, I would sit up in my bed and wait for Ye-ye to come, the second earliest riser. He'd peek into my room, and I'd hold up my arms, and he'd come and pull me out of bed. Ye-ye took me for walks in the ancient stroller. The dew still glistened on the lawns, the air had a faint chill. He'd walk me to the corner and back, all by ourselves. We felt daring in the world. This arrangement continued for years. Ye-ye coming for the summer, my brother taking all my mother's energy. Ye-ye and I only got lost once. By then I was six, and Nathan had an earache. It seemed to last the entire summer. He cried all the time. Mama was irritable. Everything I did made her tense. Same old. We began as we always had. Ye-ye and I walked hand-in-hand up the shaded sidewalks before the sun had risen high enough to burn the dew off and scorch the air. Then we went a little farther than usual, all the way to the corner, and then across that street, and up the block to the big house with gray turrets and large dense fruit trees. The owners were an elderly white couple and they had pomegranates. I'd gone on a field trip for kindergarten and I remembered the way. The nice couple had picked pomegranates from their trees and sliced them open and placed them on picnic tables covered with plastic red-and-white tablecloths. We'd all been given a quarter pomegranate to suck the seeds out of. It was morning and I was hungry, and who knew when my mother would get up and make breakfast anymore. &quot;I know a good place to go,&quot; I told Ye-ye, and we set off. But when we got to the corner, I could see the house but it was nothing like the friendly welcoming home of my memory. The tall wrought-iron gates were not tied open with streamers; there were not lines of elementary school children on the lawn with paper plates in their hands. The house was dark, shadowed, the pomegranate trees overgrown, the shade dripping from the eaves and the leaf-laden branches menacing. Even the spiky turrets of the house, which had made it seem castle-like on the field trip, now appeared threatening, as though a witch not a princess might live inside. I froze in place, Ye-ye's warm hand in mine. A bird cawed overhead. Some kind of jay. It flew into the tree, then seemed caught in the sticky darkness. Its cawing turned distressful, a shriek. I squeezed Ye-ye's hand. He patted my head. Ye-ye looked left and right. I knew he was wondering which way to go. At first I couldn't move, then all at once, I knew we needed to run. I pulled Ye-ye's hand and we turned, crossed to the sunny side of the street. I knew there was another way home. A way only in the sunshine. There was a little girl, Karen, whose house I'd gone to for a birthday party. I could picture the house, white with blue shutters, and an orange tree in the lawn, a Big Wheel on the lawn. I felt certain we could reach it. I had walked to the house with Mama pushing Nathan's stroller. We walked another block. Ye-ye followed me, patiently, trusting me. The sun was moving higher in the sky, the shadows retreating, but I didn't feel safe yet from the inky shaded witchy house. We walked and walked. And then I was lost. I knew we should turn. We turned and turned but what should have been our street, our house, our copse of avocado trees, was a different house, one with a chain-link fence and a large German Shepherd with nicked ears staring through the wire. The dog barked, his harsh voice like electric volts to my heart. Ye-ye felt it, and gripped my hand too tightly, it hurt my fingers, and he pulled me along, but he couldn't walk very fast. Still he pulled me alongside him, and I didn't dare say Ouch, until we were out of range of the dog, a block and a turn away. We could hear the echo of his bark, but he was nowhere to be seen, and he surely couldn't see us either, I hoped. We were truly lost then. There was an old white man on a lawn chair in front of one of the houses. He wore shorts and an undershirt and his belly poked out from his shorts. He held a limp hose in one hand. Water trickled from its mouth. There were patches of dirt on his lawn, and dandelions, the kind my father would not tolerate on ours. The moment a single one appeared, Papa would march out with his garden spade and his thick gloves and a plastic trash bag, and he'd dig the dandelion up, all the way to the root, and bag it, and tie the bag, and put it in the trash barrel before it could spread, he said. We were one of only a handful of Chinese families in our town in those days, and Papa felt it was important to show everyone that we understood the rules, that we knew how to keep our lawn nice, that we belonged. The white man stared at us, and Ye-ye hesitated. I knew he was thinking we could ask the man for directions, but I didn't want to. I was afraid of the man. I prayed in my thoughts, Ye-ye, no, we can't stop here. Ever since I was very little, before I could talk, I knew if I thought hard enough, Ye-ye would hear me and understand. No, Ye-ye, I prayed. We can't stop. Ye-ye understood, and we kept walking. The sun was very high overhead, and it was hot. Ye-ye was wearing his long sleeved jacket, and he stopped and took it off, and folded it in half, and half again, and tucked it under his arm. He took my right hand again in his left. My hand was hot and sticky and sweaty, but still he held me tightly. We walked until Ye-ye suddenly had to stop on some stranger's lawn. He led me to a large shade tree, and he leaned his hand against the trunk. He took out his white handkerchief and wiped his face, and neck, and then the top of his head. We were standing on the grass, which white people would not like. I knew from experience when my best friend, Gabby Ocampo, and I ran across the mean neighbor's lawn next to Gabby's house, and the old white woman had run out and shouted, &quot;You brats get off my lawn!&quot; Ye-ye sat down on the lawn and patted the grass so that I would sit next to him. I was afraid we were going to get in trouble; there were white people in the house, looking at us through a crack in the curtains of their front window. I saw them flickering there, the curtains rippling, back and forth. But I obeyed and sat on the grass. Ye-ye reached into his jacket pocket and pulled out a handful of very melted White Rabbits. Ye-ye's eyes twinkled as we both sucked on our candies, resisting the urge to chew, him because it was bad for his dentures, me out of solidarity. Except at the last minute when I absolutely couldn't stand it and I had to chomp on the candy until it was gone. Then like magic, Papa and Mama drove by in our Buick. They were driving slowly, all the windows down, and I saw them, and jumped up and ran towards them. Mama shouted, &quot;Ning-ning, don't run into the street!&quot; And I froze in place. Papa parked the car right there in the middle of the street. He jumped out of the driver's side, and I thought, We are saved! Then he ran over to me, and swatted me on the ass, once, twice, three times. &quot;Bad girl!&quot; he said. And swatted me again. I was too old for this. It wasn't the pain that made me grimace and fight back my tears as I stood there on the sidewalk in front of Ye-ye, in front of the white family who were watching from behind the curtains of their picture window. The indignity. Papa dragged me by the arm to the car. He opened the back door and said, &quot;Get in!&quot; Then he pushed me inside and I sat down, even though the hot vinyl burned the back of my legs. Then Papa went to get Ye-ye, and he helped him up slowly, and he took his arm, and walked him to the other side of the car. Mama said, &quot;Poor Ye-ye. Oh, poor Ye-ye. He could have had a stroke in this heat.&quot; Nathan was on her lap and he started to whimper. Ye-ye said something to Papa in Chinese that I couldn't understand and Papa said something in Chinese back, only very loudly, and over and over. Then Mama said, &quot;Ning-ning, what were you thinking?&quot; That's how it was, ever since Nathan was born. I was blamed for everything that went wrong. His illness, his crying all the time, his having to go to the hospital, all the tests, all the doctors. &quot;Ning-ning, I'm ashamed of you. You know you're not supposed to leave the house alone. What has gotten into you?&quot; And I thought like saying, But I wasn't alone. I was with Ye-ye. But I didn't say it. Which turned out to be a good thing, because the next thing Mama said was, &quot;You could have gotten Ye-ye killed. You're lucky we found you.&quot; And that's when I cried for real, tears and snot and shame, in front of everyone. After that, my parents became fearful. I wasn't allowed to go out by myself, and I wasn't allowed to go on walks with Ye-ye. &quot;He's forgetful. He's not himself. You're too much for him.&quot; The next year, Ye-ye didn't come for the summer at all. He stayed in his apartment in New York City with my uncle. In fact, he wouldn't visit again in person ever. Traveling had become too hard for him. However, he continued to send me White Rabbits in a box for my birthday and New Year's, along with a red envelope, every year until he died when I was eleven. I didn't have White Rabbits again until I went to China on a study abroad trip my junior year of college. In advance of Spring Festival, the street stalls were suddenly full of bins and bins of White Rabbit candies. Walking the streets around the campus of Nanjing University, I was thrilled to see the candy of my youth. I immediately bought a bag full and brought them back to the dorm. I passed them around to everyone I met. &quot;I loved these when I was a child,&quot; I explained. The old man who sat in the guardhouse at the gate politely took a handful but the women who worked in the building merely shook their heads and laughed uncomfortably. My Chinese roommate looked on in horror. &quot;My grandmother liked those,&quot; she said. I knew I was a disappointment to her. This whole mixed-nationality roommate situation was an experiment on campus, a sign of China's emergence from decades of seclusion, and was supposed to be an honor. My roommate had signed up and gone through some kind of rigorous screening process. She had been promised an American, and she'd expected some chic, blonde white girl with exotic ways and instead she got me, a Chinese American with cheap taste. Back in our room she pulled out a Toblerone roll from the drawer of her desk and popped a piece in her mouth to make her point. After that I kept my fetish to myself. But every morning when I woke, the loudspeaker outside our window blaring music for the morning exercises that my roommate and I refused to rise for, I reached from the cocoon of my comforter into the frosty air of our unheated dorm room, and pulled a new White Rabbit from the bag I kept on my desk. I untwisted the familiar white wrapper with the red and blue stripes and the rabbit outlined in blue on the side and popped the candy into my mouth. Pulling my comforter around me, I closed my eyes, as the sensuous layer of sweetened rice paper melted into the milky taffy. I'd come to Nanjing hoping to find some connection to my past, something that would perhaps console me, make up for the losses, for the sense of something missing in me, the hole that was always there in my life in America. But I was no fool. I knew that my grandfather was dead and the China of his memories was gone too, and the Chinese who lived now were rapidly throwing off the past and embracing a future of their own creation. Nothing in China was quite what I'd expected or hoped for. But secretly savoring my White Rabbit each morning gave me courage and sugar and just enough nostalgia to ready myself to get out of bed and embrace the new day.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Two Nights on 16th Street</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Two-Nights-on-16th-Street/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Two Nights on 16th Street" /><published>2018-11-01T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-11-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/two-nights-on-16th-street</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Two-Nights-on-16th-Street/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
First, I must apologize to the souls of the house
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
       Wearing the cheek bones of the mask only
&lt;br /&gt;
             Pill bottle, my name is yours
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Teeth of the mask now
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Back of the head of the mask now 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
             New phase of anti-anthropomorphism fending for real faces
&lt;br /&gt;
                       Pretending to be a drug addict by day and reading all night
&lt;br /&gt;
                                                 While economists return to rumors of oxygen
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Stuck with one of those cultures that believes I chose this family
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:right; &quot;&gt;
I am not creative
&lt;br /&gt;
Just the silliest of the revolutionaries
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Conversing with the psychic middleman
&lt;br /&gt;
Or 
&lt;br /&gt;
Wannabe mayor
&lt;br /&gt;
About hating your enemies
&lt;br /&gt;
A little more realistically
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:left; &quot;&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Our eyesight returning to red/Notepad swimming to red/Bracing for the medicine's
&lt;br /&gt;
recoil
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I need my left hand back 
&lt;br /&gt;
I broke my neck on the piano keys
&lt;br /&gt;
Found paradise in a fistfight
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Watching the universe’s last metronome
&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Some have the nerve to call a “homeless teenager”
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:right; &quot;&gt;
Just wait…
&lt;br /&gt;
These religions will start resigning in a decade or two
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Some colorfully 
&lt;br /&gt;
Some transactionally
&lt;br /&gt;
In a cotton gothic society
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Class betrayal gone glassless/ I mean ironically/ my window started fogging over too &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:right; &quot;&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I remember childhood
&lt;br /&gt;
Remember the word “Childhood” being a beginning 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
A poet loses his mind, you know, like the room has weather
&lt;br /&gt;
Or first-girlfriend gravity
&lt;br /&gt;
Poem gravity 
&lt;br /&gt;
Mind-game gravity
&lt;br /&gt;
Or revolution languishing behind 
&lt;br /&gt;
The sugar in my good friend’s mind
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The difference between me and you
&lt;br /&gt;
Is that the madness
&lt;br /&gt;
Wants me forever&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:right; &quot;&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Bright lights behind hyena eyes,
&lt;br /&gt;
I mean, if I had to fall in love today
&lt;br /&gt;
My grandchildren would be doomed 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
A pair of apartments
&lt;br /&gt;
      Defining both my family
&lt;br /&gt;
      And political composure
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Books behind my back
&lt;br /&gt;
Bail money paved into the streets
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Playing:
&lt;br /&gt;
Euphoria
&lt;br /&gt;
Euphoria
&lt;br /&gt;
Cliché&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:right;&quot;&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Sharing a dirty deli sandwich with my friend
&lt;br /&gt;
A cosmic tool counted on by scared people
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Psychology of the mask now
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Teeth of the mask again
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- End of page --&gt;
&lt;!-- Start of Bottom Footer --&gt;

&lt;nav class=&quot;nav justify-content-center&quot; style=&quot;box-shadow: 0 2px 2px -2px rgba(0,0,0,0);&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;nav-container&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;//&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h2 class=&quot;nav-title&quot;&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul style=&quot;position: relative&quot;&gt;
      &lt;!-- &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;//&quot;&gt;Issue&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; --&gt;
      &lt;li class=&quot;nav-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;nav-link&quot; href=&quot;//2018-fall&quot;&gt;2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li class=&quot;nav-item&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;|&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li class=&quot;nav-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;nav-link&quot; href=&quot;//2019-fall&quot;&gt;2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li class=&quot;nav-item&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;|&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li class=&quot;nav-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;nav-link&quot; href=&quot;//people&quot;&gt;People&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li class=&quot;nav-item&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;|&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li class=&quot;nav-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;nav-link&quot; href=&quot;//about&quot;&gt;About&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/nav&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;container&quot;&gt;

  &lt;section id=&quot;sec1&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//dodie-bellamy/&quot;&gt;Dodie Bellamy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//The-Violence-of-the-Image/&quot;&gt;The Violence of the Image&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Stuff-My-Stalker-Has-Ordered-for-Me-Online/&quot;&gt;Stuff My Stalker Has Ordered for Me Online&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//may-lee-chai/&quot;&gt;May-lee Chai&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//White-Rabbits/&quot;&gt;White Rabbits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//tongo-eisen-martin/&quot;&gt;Tongo Eisen-Martin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Fish-With-Ambition-to-Become-the-River/&quot;&gt;Fish With Ambition to Become the River&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Two-Nights-on-16th-Street/&quot;&gt;Two Nights on 16th Street&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Many-Does-To-Go-Or-Turns-The-Pen/&quot;&gt;Many Doses To Go Or Turns the Pen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//jennifer-firestone/&quot;&gt;Jennifer Firestone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Selections-from-Ten/&quot;&gt;Selections from Ten&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/section&gt;
  &lt;section id=&quot;sec2&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//sheila-heti/&quot;&gt;Sheila Heti&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Literature-Against-Anxiety/&quot;&gt;Literature Against Anxiety&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//lorelei-lee/&quot;&gt;Lorelei Lee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Leaving-San-Francisco/&quot;&gt;Leaving San Francisco&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//miranda-mellis/&quot;&gt;Miranda Mellis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//The-Imperceptible-Utopia/&quot;&gt;The Imperceptible Utopia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//To-Not-Become-a-Pillar-of-Salt/&quot;&gt;To Not Become a Pillar of Salt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//christopher-merrill/&quot;&gt;Christopher Merrill&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Rustams-Throne/&quot;&gt;Rustam's Throne&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/section&gt;
  &lt;section id=&quot;sec3&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//katherine-min/&quot;&gt;Katherine Min&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//On-Being-a-Sprinter/&quot;&gt;On Being a Sprinter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//On-Being-Humpty-Dumpty/&quot;&gt;On Being Humpty Dumpty&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//laura-mullen/&quot;&gt;Laura Mullen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Scream/&quot;&gt;Scream&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Elsie-Disclaimer/&quot;&gt;Elsie (Disclaimer)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Elsie-The-Coward/&quot;&gt;Elsie The Coward&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Elsie-Doesnt-Mind/&quot;&gt;Elsie Doesn't Mind&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//El-C-the-C/&quot;&gt;El C the C&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//The-Imaginary-Begins/&quot;&gt;The Imaginary Begins&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//C-Section/&quot;&gt;C Section&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Queen-of-Muses/&quot;&gt;Queen of Muses&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//ron-silliman/&quot;&gt;Ron Silliman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//from-Parrot-Eyes-Lust/&quot;&gt;from Parrot Eyes Lust&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//ross-simonini/&quot;&gt;Ross Simonini&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Interview-with-Paul-McCarthy/&quot;&gt;Legs Spread, Mask On:  Reflections on Snow White, Deleuze, and Late Capitalism&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/section&gt;
  &lt;section id=&quot;sec4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//john-yau/&quot;&gt;John Yau&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//The-Presidents-Second-Telegram/&quot;&gt;The President's Second Telegram&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//The-Presidents-Telegram-3/&quot;&gt;The President's Telegram (3)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//The-Congressmans-Explination/&quot;&gt;The Congressman's Explanation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/section&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Tongo Eisen-Martin</name></author><category term="20181111" /><summary type="html">First, I must apologize to the souls of the house        Wearing the cheek bones of the mask only              Pill bottle, my name is yours Teeth of the mask now Back of the head of the mask now               New phase of anti-anthropomorphism fending for real faces                        Pretending to be a drug addict by day and reading all night                                                  While economists return to rumors of oxygen Stuck with one of those cultures that believes I chose this family</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">To Not Become a Pillar of Salt</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/To-Not-Become-a-Pillar-of-Salt/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="To Not Become a Pillar of Salt" /><published>2018-11-01T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-11-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/to-not-become-a-pillar-of-salt</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/To-Not-Become-a-Pillar-of-Salt/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I don’t particularly go in for telling stories, I like to forget things, I forget things on purpose, but if you held a gun to my head and told me that you’d kill me if I didn’t tell you a story–I know what story I would tell you. It’s something that happened to me when I was twenty–four years old that I entirely forgot about (I told you I forget about things on purpose) until yesterday.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I had moved to a small island, population 410. I worked for a small company. The directors made me nervous, but I assumed it was just the natural nervousness of a new job and that it would fade with time. It never did. I never got over the feeling of intimidation I felt around them.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
But I learned to act very natural at work. The first day, they gave me what turned out to be my only assignment. “Please, make a spreadsheet of all sources of private funding available from organizations which contained the following code somewhere in their documentation at some point over the past three decades: IjkeRt5671_410.” This arcane task became my whole job. It was hard for me to tell what the funds were for as I dutifully logged the data. The language of the documents they had me searching was nominally English, but beyond my ken. “Specialized.”
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was on the outer circle of the outer circle, a paid gleaner of obscure documents and an occasional proofreader for banal white papers that contained no discernible substance. But I’m ashamed to say I didn’t care: I was indifferent to what they were doing. Vague, embarrassing, and unfulfilled longings for sex and revelation preoccupied me, dampening the faculty of curiosity. I put in my eight hours and I went home.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
My employers worked constantly, every day and night, but they didn’t expect me to. I took weekends for myself, though I never left the island. They left me alone on my days off, never calling or intruding on my nights or weekends. As a result, when, about six months into working for them, I saw their number on my phone in the middle of the day on a Saturday, I thought they must have an important reason to call.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I had been at the beach looking at the ocean, not really thinking about anything or doing anything important, just sort of enjoying my raw surroundings and pondering the idea of swimming for the first time since I had moved to the island for the job earlier that year.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
My days were stultifying, spent at a desk. I was an assembly line information worker, unable to interpret what I was doing in any meaningful way, even if I &lt;em&gt;had&lt;/em&gt; cared to (I had given analysis one or two half–hearted tries). I had begun to exist in a perpetual, cobwebbed haze. I had no motivation to do anything creative during my time off and often spent the weekends in a broody stupor, napping, watching movies, staring at the ocean, and reading magazines. But after all, I had aspirations, and it was clear I couldn’t wake myself up on my own. It occurred to me that a plunge into the ocean might be salutary. I had confined myself to admiring the ocean from afar until then, avoided getting to know it on the inside. But on that day, I felt I needed an ordeal. One difficult, delightful, naked and cold–as–fuck slip down, and I’d emerge all new and erased, an elemental reboot. I’d get in and then right back out, cleaving to the shore–I’m not much of a swimmer, to say the least, and the North Atlantic is rough, cold, and full of jellyfish. I was after a wake up, not a negative shock. (And by negative shock, you know what I mean. Even a baby knows what I mean.)
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I had just determined in my mind to get into the water, but had not yet moved, when my phone rang. I answered. It was R., my supervisor. Without any preamble she said, “Please, don’t go swimming.”
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I had never heard her &lt;em&gt;say please&lt;/em&gt; before. I told myself to respond but I was at a loss.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
And then I suddenly realized that since I had not responded, had barely even breathed since first answering the phone, I could pretend that I hadn’t heard her, act like the reception had cut out. I could give a fake response to her fake request. I told my shaking self that that I had a right to–it was the weekend. I felt an imperative to restore normalcy by pretending that this phone call had not happened, as much to myself as to her. Whatever it meant that my employer knew I had intended to go swimming at that moment, even though I was alone and had only &lt;em&gt;thought&lt;/em&gt; about it, I did not want to know. And whatever it meant that she was invading my privacy and instructing me &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; to, I was even less inclined to know.&lt;nobr&gt; I warbled, “. . . the reception&lt;/nobr&gt; is bad here, &lt;nobr&gt;I can’t hear you . . . are you there?”&lt;/nobr&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Possibly it was obvious to R. that I was lying, but that didn’t matter to me. Her call had released me from the obligation to respect reality. I hung up, turned off the phone, and flung it away from me. I ran to the flat where I had been living, and, with a note of regret, which chimed briefly in the cathedral of my relief, I hurriedly packed my few things and caught the next ferry off the island and erased the whole episode from my mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- End of page --&gt;
&lt;!-- Start of Bottom Footer --&gt;

&lt;nav class=&quot;nav justify-content-center&quot; style=&quot;box-shadow: 0 2px 2px -2px rgba(0,0,0,0);&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;nav-container&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;//&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h2 class=&quot;nav-title&quot;&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul style=&quot;position: relative&quot;&gt;
      &lt;!-- &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;//&quot;&gt;Issue&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; --&gt;
      &lt;li class=&quot;nav-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;nav-link&quot; href=&quot;//2018-fall&quot;&gt;2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li class=&quot;nav-item&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;|&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li class=&quot;nav-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;nav-link&quot; href=&quot;//2019-fall&quot;&gt;2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li class=&quot;nav-item&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;|&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li class=&quot;nav-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;nav-link&quot; href=&quot;//people&quot;&gt;People&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li class=&quot;nav-item&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;|&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li class=&quot;nav-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;nav-link&quot; href=&quot;//about&quot;&gt;About&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/nav&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;container&quot;&gt;

  &lt;section id=&quot;sec1&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//dodie-bellamy/&quot;&gt;Dodie Bellamy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//The-Violence-of-the-Image/&quot;&gt;The Violence of the Image&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Stuff-My-Stalker-Has-Ordered-for-Me-Online/&quot;&gt;Stuff My Stalker Has Ordered for Me Online&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//may-lee-chai/&quot;&gt;May-lee Chai&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//White-Rabbits/&quot;&gt;White Rabbits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//tongo-eisen-martin/&quot;&gt;Tongo Eisen-Martin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Fish-With-Ambition-to-Become-the-River/&quot;&gt;Fish With Ambition to Become the River&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Two-Nights-on-16th-Street/&quot;&gt;Two Nights on 16th Street&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Many-Does-To-Go-Or-Turns-The-Pen/&quot;&gt;Many Doses To Go Or Turns the Pen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//jennifer-firestone/&quot;&gt;Jennifer Firestone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Selections-from-Ten/&quot;&gt;Selections from Ten&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/section&gt;
  &lt;section id=&quot;sec2&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//sheila-heti/&quot;&gt;Sheila Heti&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Literature-Against-Anxiety/&quot;&gt;Literature Against Anxiety&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//lorelei-lee/&quot;&gt;Lorelei Lee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Leaving-San-Francisco/&quot;&gt;Leaving San Francisco&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//miranda-mellis/&quot;&gt;Miranda Mellis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//The-Imperceptible-Utopia/&quot;&gt;The Imperceptible Utopia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//To-Not-Become-a-Pillar-of-Salt/&quot;&gt;To Not Become a Pillar of Salt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//christopher-merrill/&quot;&gt;Christopher Merrill&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Rustams-Throne/&quot;&gt;Rustam's Throne&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/section&gt;
  &lt;section id=&quot;sec3&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//katherine-min/&quot;&gt;Katherine Min&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//On-Being-a-Sprinter/&quot;&gt;On Being a Sprinter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//On-Being-Humpty-Dumpty/&quot;&gt;On Being Humpty Dumpty&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//laura-mullen/&quot;&gt;Laura Mullen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Scream/&quot;&gt;Scream&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Elsie-Disclaimer/&quot;&gt;Elsie (Disclaimer)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Elsie-The-Coward/&quot;&gt;Elsie The Coward&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Elsie-Doesnt-Mind/&quot;&gt;Elsie Doesn't Mind&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//El-C-the-C/&quot;&gt;El C the C&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//The-Imaginary-Begins/&quot;&gt;The Imaginary Begins&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//C-Section/&quot;&gt;C Section&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Queen-of-Muses/&quot;&gt;Queen of Muses&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//ron-silliman/&quot;&gt;Ron Silliman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//from-Parrot-Eyes-Lust/&quot;&gt;from Parrot Eyes Lust&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//ross-simonini/&quot;&gt;Ross Simonini&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Interview-with-Paul-McCarthy/&quot;&gt;Legs Spread, Mask On:  Reflections on Snow White, Deleuze, and Late Capitalism&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/section&gt;
  &lt;section id=&quot;sec4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//john-yau/&quot;&gt;John Yau&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//The-Presidents-Second-Telegram/&quot;&gt;The President's Second Telegram&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//The-Presidents-Telegram-3/&quot;&gt;The President's Telegram (3)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//The-Congressmans-Explination/&quot;&gt;The Congressman's Explanation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/section&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Miranda Mellis</name></author><category term="20181111" /><summary type="html">I don’t particularly go in for telling stories, I like to forget things, I forget things on purpose, but if you held a gun to my head and told me that you’d kill me if I didn’t tell you a story–I know what story I would tell you. It’s something that happened to me when I was twenty–four years old that I entirely forgot about (I told you I forget about things on purpose) until yesterday. I had moved to a small island, population 410. I worked for a small company. The directors made me nervous, but I assumed it was just the natural nervousness of a new job and that it would fade with time. It never did. I never got over the feeling of intimidation I felt around them. But I learned to act very natural at work. The first day, they gave me what turned out to be my only assignment. “Please, make a spreadsheet of all sources of private funding available from organizations which contained the following code somewhere in their documentation at some point over the past three decades: IjkeRt5671_410.” This arcane task became my whole job. It was hard for me to tell what the funds were for as I dutifully logged the data. The language of the documents they had me searching was nominally English, but beyond my ken. “Specialized.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Violence of the Image</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/The-Violence-of-the-Image/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Violence of the Image" /><published>2018-11-01T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-11-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/the-violence-of-the-image</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/The-Violence-of-the-Image/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Last month the 1959 low-budget monster movie &lt;em&gt;Behemoth&lt;/em&gt; was on TV. I watched just the ending. The Behemoth, which looks like an elongated dinosaur with bulgy eyes, wiggles mechanically through the ocean. It’s way bigger than the submarine that’s trying to destroy it. Wham! It bashes against the side of the sub and water starts leaking from an overhead pipe, provoking tense meaningful eye contact between the two officers manning the controls. They maneuver for a better aim. One yells, “Fire!” and the other grits his teeth and presses a plunger, unloading a bomb that hits the monster in the head. It thrashes and sinks. “That’s it?” I thought. “They killed the thing with one shot?”  These days it would take at least 15 minutes of fast-cut struggle, for we citizens of the 21st century have learned that evil does not die easily. No longer is evil focused like a bad tooth you can root out and get on with your good life. Increasingly diffuse, the Big Scary now spreads across networks, sprouting anywhere. We have global warming; we have public executions that shock without warning; we have toxic waters, honey bees threatened with extinction, warnings of plague. In the White House, Americans have installed an irrational, lying, unaccountable crook who rages against “radical Islamic terrorists,” an embarrassingly redundant term. Isn’t radical implied in terrorist? Have you ever heard of a middle brow terrorist? A centrist terrorist? A give-a-cop-a-can-of-Pepsi-and-heal-the-world terrorist? When you’re an American, you’ve got so much to be embarrassed about. The U.S. has become a very stupid country, and stupidity married to power is danger squared. We’ve given a buffoon the nuclear code.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
To be radical you need a wall to bounce your radicalism off of. When you live in a soup of cover ups, corruption, and general smarminess, is it possible to clear the mire enough to even find that wall? Those on the radical left claim—and rightly so—that global capitalism is the enemy. But late capitalism is a slippery beast, able to incorporate just about anything into its ravenous maw and spit it back out with a price tag attached. Blind, profit-driven virulence has infiltrated everything, its poison creeping both inside and outside of us. The Behemoth has swallowed the submarine and here we are, flailing in the slimy dark. In another 1950s cult favorite, &lt;em&gt;The Wild One&lt;/em&gt;, a dancing blonde asks biker Marlon Brando, “Hey, Johnny, what are you rebelling against?” He bongos the top of a jukebox and snarls, “Whatta ya got?” What do we “got”? That is the central question facing us today. Without a focus, without a specific monster in mind to boom boom boom, radical enthusiasm can grind down to depression. We stop reading the news; we post pix of cats on Facebook, flowers on Instagram, obsessively checking for Likes. Or, like overcrowded rodents, we attack one another.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I’ve got a stalker. I used to be her favorite writer, but when I posted bad opinions in the comments box of another poet’s Facebook thread, her admiration switched to disdain. She instantly hated me and all I stood for, even things I didn’t realize I stood for, and she began an assault across social media, ridiculing and accusing me. I find it difficult, today, to forgive the poets who left encouraging comments for her. I felt shunned and despised, like there was no love in the world for me. Presently emails from online shopping sites began appearing in my in-box, confirming orders I didn’t order, informing me my credit card had been declined. My stalker is a monster. She wouldn’t argue with this. Making herself into a monster makes her feel special. It is difficult for the entitled to feel special. Tattoos and heavy eyeliner and revealing little dresses—everybody—even fat girls—has those. She posts pictures of her ass to social media; she likes pastries and favors the word “super.” My stalker is a bully. A bully can smell someone who has been previously bullied—the bully and the bullied fit together like jigsaw puzzle pieces. I imagine her alone in the middle of the night, ashtray on her nightstand overflowing with butts, drunk, or buzzed on Adderall, maybe both, afraid to sleep due to last night’s bout of sleep paralysis, the tension is unbearable—tight jaw compacted heart—she searches for something crappy online—adds it to her shopping cart, enters my name address phone number, which she copied down the summer she interned for that radical indie press—her taut little body vibrates as she enters a fake credit card number, presses the PLACE ORDER button, pummeling me with hubcaps peonies guitar strings silk sock liners—what a fucking rush what a release—almost as good as the burst she gets when she slices her inner thigh with a razor blade—it’s like she’s sending me all her pain, her disappointment her god-awful ordinariness. Afterwards she feels a terrible intimacy, that of the torturer who comes to love her victim.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
With the election of Trump, poets decided that the only acceptable way to depict an American flag was upside down. When a provocateur poet posted a flag rightside up on Instagram, there was an angry Facebook thread about it. Poet A said that if he had known the flag poet was so fucked up, he never would have had him read in his series. Poets B and C proposed informing the flag poet’s employer about the offense and getting him fired. None of the poets noticed that the posted flag wasn’t a real American flag, but the fake Chinese-made flag that had been in the news, the one that unwitting patriots had purchased, with too many stars. Kevin back channeled poet B and pointed this out:  &lt;em&gt;That is not the regular flag. It has far too many stars. It is the 61-star flag that indicates the alternate history of America. Whether or not that’s a good thing or a bad depends how you feel about the flag today, and if you believe that the U.S. took a wrong turn somewhere back in history. The regular flag has only 50 stars—supposedly for each state in the union.&lt;/em&gt; However, poet B didn’t back down. He said he couldn’t understand what a 61-star flag would signify. He said that regardless of the flag poet’s intention, to be oblique on something this sensitive was aggressive, and the rightside up flag still reinscribed violence.  If one is vague, poets will project the worst into your words. If you refer to a person but don’t name names, poets will assume it’s themselves or someone you’d never dream of. At Alley Cat Books the reader launches into a poem so politically correct you could bounce a dime off of it, political in all the right ways—and a poet in the audience starts nodding his head wildly back and forth as if it were a rattle. The rest of the reading he has a normal head. Political writing is straightforward, plain, and “learned,” prefaced by a declaration of the author’s identity markers.  &lt;em&gt;As a white cis American working class college-educated Baby Boomer who lives in California and prefers unoaked Chardonnay. …&lt;/em&gt;  Political writing is careful about who owns what experience. Someone tweets:  &lt;em&gt;She doesn’t have the right to talk about that,&lt;/em&gt; and you feel shame. When a poet rants against me and the politics of my writing on Facebook, she begins with “What kind of woman would. …”  &lt;em&gt;What kind of woman&lt;/em&gt; implies a correct, proper version of femaleness—and I—not being that kind of woman—have crossed over into an impossible otherness. It doesn’t matter what else she goes on to accuse me of, &lt;em&gt;What kind of woman&lt;/em&gt; has declared me an abomination. Since childhood I’ve been criticized for my nonstandard female embodiment. I was savage and unruly, clomping through life like a bull—and now I’m an old white feminist—an oppressor in a pink pussy hat.  The Facebook poet’s curses scatter across my features like the points in facial recognition software, a surveillance grid that hardens on my face like a mask. No expression is possible in the tightness of her projections. Thought criminals need to be rooted out and shunned, the dead as well as the living. Cindy Sherman. Gandhi. Marjorie Perloff. Walt Whitman. &lt;em&gt;And what I assume you shall assume,/ For every atom belonging to me as good belongs to you.&lt;/em&gt;  Community walks within me and thus I contain both criminal and accuser. The idiocy of the American government, I contain that as well. In a muck of warring poets, I spew that war. Heriberto Yépez: &lt;em&gt;Networks are both migrants and the gatekeepers.&lt;/em&gt; The madness of social media, it too walks within me. I operate in the dangerous and contradictory realm of the in-between. Neither goddess nor heroine, I am an old white feminist, a shriveled hag envious of my stalker’s fertility and youthful beauty. My hair is coarse and unkempt; my long hanging dugs bounce about like phalluses. I befoul Poetry with my personal essays, which are riddled with superstition, deceit, defective intelligence, lust, and debauchery. I am simultaneously horrific and ridiculous. My politics are so odious I’ve made pacts with rapists. Though he’s taken the form of a goat, I kiss the abuser’s backside; I apologize for him.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
In a skit called “Silver Surfers,” Tracey Ullman plays a teacher who shows seniors how to troll the internet. A woman says she’d like to see her grandson’s YouTube channel. Tracey turns on a video of a grade school boy demonstrating something. She notes how the video is amateurish in quality, and tells the class that when you see somebody getting it wrong online it’s important to point it out to them. Tracey instructs the class to click the thumbs down button—or if they want to make it more personal to post a comment, using a fake name, in which they say either he has a voice like a girl or everyone here wishes he were dead. Tracey types on the grandmother’s computer, “Wish you were dead, loser.” “It’s a real thrill when you click that send button,” she says.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The internet, like late capitalism, is everywhere and nowhere. My stalker sends me objects that are not objects. They’re images I keep trying to push into language. According to capitalism, what you own you are. Lawn plants, chenille bedspread, frilly dresses, Forest Friends felt Christmas ornament kit, fish pond water conditioner, hubcaps. What is the stalker saying to/about me through these suburban talismans? According to capitalism, whoever controls images controls the world. I say to my psychic, I think I know who’s been stalking me, but I’m not sure. My psychic says, &lt;em&gt;you know&lt;/em&gt;. How can I control these images that have been thrust upon me? I imagine a woman who wears floral dresses, a widow with a four-year old toddler. She loved her husband and always wears a peridot pendant that contains a bit of his ashes. She’s a photographer who plays the cello and drives a motorcycle. Alone in the house she feels vulnerable, so she keeps a gun under her pillow. She has a home office, a file box where she stores her photos. She’s femmy and a bit old fashioned. She sleeps under a tufted chenille bedspread; she uses face firming creams and bikini exfoliators. She’s trying to fix herself up to get another man. She gardens, preferring bulb plants from Holland—so she lives somewhere with a yard, a rural or suburban landscape. People do not suspect her wildness—the gun, the motorcycle—but it’s there waiting to take over. She likes bargains, preferring to buy things on sale, with coupon codes or open boxes. She has a Blu-ray player to help her through her lonely nights. Or maybe she met a man who owns a gun. He’s a rebel who deserves her bikini-groomed snatch. This new man likes porn; when she’s ready he plans to share some with her on the Samsung Blu-ray player he noticed in the living room. They sit in her garden with its lush greens, irises, and peonies, holding hands, kissing lightly, then more and more passionately. Let’s make it the guy who has the motorcycle. He’s a Marlon Brando type—a vet who’s living off of disability—going to art school in photography, and these things my stalker ordered are gifts for him, the wheel, the gun cleaner, the camera. She drives a car—a fully restored 61 Dodge Polara, which totally impresses the vet. That’s how they met—at a light he pulled up beside her on his motorcycle and asked her if she wanted to grab some coffee. After the coffee, the woman and the photographer fuck in the garden beside the koi pond, which is mercifully devoid of chlorine fumes thanks to Tetra Pond AquaSafe Tap Water Conditioner. Their sex is protected from nosey neighbors by a clump of kingsize hostas. The female koi are named after female science fiction writers, Doris Lessing, Octavia Butler; the male fish are named after 20th century avant garde composers, Boulez, Webern. Last week raccoons ate Ursula K. Le Guin, and before that they got Joanna Russ and Schoenberg, so that the woman is considering replacing the koi with a cheaper species, such as goldfish. The vet’s cock is pink and clean, squeaky clean like the Army taught him to keep it in their anti-VD training videos, well-scrubbed as his gun, the barrel of which he regularly plunges with Brownells Moly Bore Treatment Paste. The woman’s Diane von Furstenberg dress is pushed up to her waist. The vet pulls out his Nikon Coolpix and shoots a close up of the twig and gravel scratches on her ass. The Samsung Blu-ray player blasts “Bang a Gong.” HUBCAP DIAMOND STAR HALO. According to capitalism, accessories are personality. Commodities morph into character traits, morph into narrative momentum. Personal memories and product reviews on Amazon provide supplemental details. My fuck scene would be more erotic if there were more of a buildup but the woman is always ready. Too eager, perhaps. She can come without touching herself. Her cunt is so strong it could lift barbells, if she owned any. Sometimes the photographer complains she’s clenching him too tightly, but her cunt is ravenous for him, wants to absorb every drop his cock can offer. Afterwards she doesn’t wash, enjoying his semen smeared over her legs and belly, dripping out of her, and besides, the stalker hasn’t ordered her any soap.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The first target of massive internet shaming and harassment was Monica Lewinsky, in 1998. She was 22 years old and, being the first, she had no context or support to help her cope. These days she finds comfort and purpose in her work with anti-harassment and bullying organizations. Her taped phone conversations with Linda Tripp are available on YouTube, hours of rambling female intimacy. I envy the closeness of the two women, the way they coddle the micro details of one another’s lives—everything from the temptation of donuts at the hairdresser—Monica’s favorite is white frosting with multi-colored sprinkles—to why won’t Bill call me. The conversations begin after Clinton has dumped Monica and track her heartbreak and desperate attempts to contact him. I’d love to have a girlfriend I could talk to endlessly about all my shit—someone as doting and supportive as Linda, someone who would slather me with such love. The betrayal by Tripp alone would devastate anyone—and that’s just a footnote to Monica’s collapse. If old white feminists ruled the world, one woman defiling another would be a capital offense.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
On Facebook, a male poet posts a photo of a naked man striding down the street. In the comments section, a female poet writes she finds the photo so upsetting her hands are shaking, and she just has to speak out. She’s decided the person in the photo is a mentally ill homeless man—even though there is nothing in the photo or the male poet’s post that announces that. Her extreme reaction to her (own) invented narrative prompts her to condemn the male poet and the hundred people who liked the image. I read on the internet that suggesting self-control online is &lt;em&gt;tone policing&lt;/em&gt;, and I am wrong to go there. Maybe she’s right, we’re all a bunch of assholes laughing at the disenfranchised—or maybe he’s a gay nudist—in San Francisco it’s not uncommon to see naked men walking down the street, alone or in groups. The photo is of the man’s back, taken at a distance, maybe he has a glittering gold tube sock stuck on his cock. I’ve seen so many men with socks on their cocks—including panhandling teens on Castro Street. To get more money, I assume. No matter how much you stare at the image, it refuses to cough up more clues. Is it possible to keep your righteous fingers away from the keyboard? Is it possible to live without diminishing or oppressing another? Jain ascetics with soft broomsmade of shed peacock feathers, gently sweeping the ground lest they step on an insect. What are the limits of reverence?
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
We make soup, we write tight little narratives where all messy threads are tied up, neatly, at the end. We read books on organizing our home. Rooms turn vast with order, with simplicity. We have only what we need, what we cherish, and there is a place for everything we own. Possessions are instantly findable and they are happy to serve us. The stalker destroys time, categories, and meaning, locking memories and dreams in the present moment. The mind strains against the body to push thoughts out. Everything is impure. The daily taunts and jeers I experienced as a child are happening right now right here. I’m pooping my guts out, taking slow breaths against the pain. My body is twisting my subjectivity, wringing it out like one of those old-time washing machines my grandmother had. Whenever anyone laughs they are laughing at me. The stalker has broken the frame. The process of writing this essay creates a new frame that proves I am capable of at least the most basic adult human functioning. How do you express trauma when linearity fails you? You order products online for your enemy. When the past possesses the present you enter the now now now of spurting adrenaline, and your irises spin like pinwheels. The pix shriek nobody wants you here the pix shriek you are hated everybody hates you. I publish a piece in a journal my stalker has also published in. I imagine her reading it with scorn, searching for bits out of context she can use to destroy me. “Dodie Bellamy said” becomes a tagline to ruin. On &lt;em&gt;Nashville&lt;/em&gt;, Will, the gay character, is being bashed on Twitter and bam! his trauma is my trauma panic blots out the present like one of those bags terrorists shove over a captive’s head. I am forever a child useless and humiliated. I am a radiant pink clit inflamed by the eros of my stalker’s loathing.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
My stalker hates capitalism. I believe she hates capitalism more than she hates me. Headline on the internet: &lt;em&gt;A majority of millennials now reject capitalism, poll shows&lt;/em&gt;. My stalker says that if she could have anything in the world she wished for, it would be to destroy capitalism. My stalker believes that by shoplifting items made by slaves in China she is fucking capitalism. When I was young I’d shoplift with friends but I was too much of a pussy to do it on my own. My friend Jackie—who was a pro—and I would come home with huge hauls of stuff, most of which I’d end up not wanting, and I had to figure out how to get rid of. Before we went on a run, we’d put on makeup and work dresses and little heels; our aesthetic was &lt;em&gt;clueless middle class bargain hunter&lt;/em&gt;. Jackie’s first rule: no backpacks or large purses while shoplifting. We carried moderately-sized shoulder bags. They looked like they couldn’t hold much of anything—but you’d be surprised. I once smashed a fluffy pink prom dress into one. Jackie’s second rule was entitlement. When she found a stainless steel fish poacher she liked, she just picked it up and marched out of Macy’s with it, and nobody blinked. Despite its heart-thumping arousal, hours of nonstop shoplifting was exhausting. I felt buried in commodity culture and the treadmill of consumption that drives capitalism’s insatiable thrust. It was gross. When Jackie and I returned to my apartment, we dumped our haul onto my bed in a jumbled mountain, and then we belly-flopped onto it, shrieking, carefree as dogs rolling around in shit.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
One night, over a period two hours, thirteen things were ordered in my name, each from a different website. Then a coupleof hours later, another item, bringing the total to fourteen in one evening. Could one person possibly have ordered this much, this quickly? Or was somebody throwing a Harass Dodie party? I sat down at my desk and started emailing the companies—This order is fraudulent. I also downloaded the product photos per artist friend Kristina Lee Podesva’s suggestion. When I told her about my stalker, excitement spread across Kristina’s face and she exclaimed, “Document this!” The order confirmations were coming in so furiously I couldn’t keep up. I could only imagine that the person on the other end was tweaking. I checked my stalker’s Twitter feed. She tweeted before the ordering frenzy began and then not again until ten or fifteen minutes after it ended, when she wrote—My mother just asked me if I was on heroin. A few minutes later she tweeted—I’m reading in Philadelphia, if you come bring me flowers—peonies. Peony bulbs were one of the fourteen items. The world goes crazy with connection. I say to my psychic, I think I know who it is, but I’m not sure. My psychic says, &lt;em&gt;you know&lt;/em&gt;.  My stalker sends me a widow’s walk and a necklace to contain the ashes of a loved one—is she casting a spell of doom on me? What does an office chair mean? It requires work for me to write back to all these companies, but it also requires a hell of a lot of commitment and focused attention for her to order all this stuff.  Her curated images are about potential, about our post-industrial condition, in which we sit at machines pushing around bytes, alone, longing to reach out.  Glamor shots of merchandise hail her and she clicks them with the grammarless fever of a rat clicking a food-delivery lever. Eventually the image objects arrive on my computer and I click them with confusion and fear and anger, but also with a twinge of pleasure that reminds me of playing &lt;em&gt;Monument Valley&lt;/em&gt;, my bumbling attempts to navigate a twisting architecture whose rules endlessly elude. Objects speak with the indeterminacy of a cry, garbled like puppets with their lips sewn shut. Yet it’s impossible not to narrativize them. To the protest, my stalker wears cotton toddler panties stretched tight across her cooch. Beneath her sheer Diane Von Furstenberg dress, areolas bloom, lush pink peonies. Comrades and government infiltrators alike find her unbearably sexy. Anything you send a writer is a gift. A suicidal young woman pulls up on a motorcycle. I rub her face into my desiccated crotch, suck the bloom from her cheeks and cough up bile. My breath is so foul sperm curdles and young Marxists faint. &lt;em&gt;I too am not a bit tamed, I too am untranslatable,/ I sound my barbaric yawp over the roofs of the world&lt;/em&gt;.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Before I became a middle class person I shopped only at thrift stores, so the clothes I owned were jeans, striped long-sleeved tees, and party dresses. When I got my first middle class job, I went to Macy’s and charged these awful outfits—polyester pants suits, etc.—I looked like a clown, a droopy professional clown. The middle class likes different things than the working class, but we all want things things things things—even homeless people in my neighborhood wheel shopping carts and suitcases overflowing with things. If capitalism were destroyed, would the homeless have better things? The viscosity of capitalism swallows us. We are never sure if we are inside or outside of it. It spreads over the globe making things stick together. I walk down the street wearing bits of China India Portugal Vietnam, and occasionally the USA. The ghosts of nameless workers vape from my silhouette, rendering me not one but many.  My boss said my best middle class outfit was one I shoplifted with Jackie—a navy cashmere shift by Ralph Lauren. For the bourgeois subject wouldn’t guilt be a more appropriate response than hate? Perhaps guilt is what’s really behind the attacking of those perceived politically impure. Like a game of tag, you spread the cooties to those not deft enough to sidestep your fingering. Anyone who’s seen a zombie movie knows that when capitalism is destroyed we don’t get utopia. We get poetry bandits who police the perimeters. Law like a person has an unconscious. What my stalker really wants to destroy is the stink of trauma that wafts off of her.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I provide a focal point for my stalker’s hate, a manageable target for the all-consuming vastness of her rage. If she didn’t have me, maybe she’d jump off a bridge or shoot up a post office, who knows. It’s the middle of the night and all this pressure is trapped in her body, enormous pressure she can’t release. She wants to sigh, to scream, to burst out crying. But nothing moves. Stuck in a limbo of angst, where sadness and fury are all mucked up together, ongoing and escalating, my stalker looks over her list of enemies. It’s Dodie tonight. People rarely do things just to be wicked—they act because they’re convinced they’ve encountered evil, convinced that innocents need protecting—or they perceive their livelihood is threatened—or a great wrong has been committed against them. Throughout history, horrible things—I don’t need to list them—have been done with God on our side, things that must have felt honorable at the time, but whose cruelty today shocks us. Powerful feelings can fuck you up, especially when fucked-up you feel you have the right to fuck up others. On the internet I read about a guy who stalked a woman for five years. Helen reported 125 incidents of harassment but the police did nothing until he attacked her with a pair of scissors, stabbing her multiple times on the neck, face, and back.  It took a lot of googling to find out what Helen did to deserve her “living nightmare.”  She met Joseph at a halfway house where she was recovering from an eating disorder. They became friends, until one night Joseph asked Helen to drive him and another friend to see a band called Carnaby Street. Helen didn’t feel up to it and said she’d text him if she changed her mind. Joseph felt stood up, and his affection for Helen instantly turned into burning hatred. So he vandalized her car, made silent phone calls, left a dead cat on her doorstep, smashed her windows, sent her letters calling her fat and rat-faced, spray-painted Die Helen across a brick wall, nearly killed her. Because she didn’t go to a concert. There is always a reason to destroy another. Anybody who needs a reason will find one. I was my stalker’s favorite writer until I posted a comment on a poet’s Facebook thread, three years ago.  Before that I have no memory of having met her or heard of her. Though I think that’s not true; most likely I was in many rooms with her, rooms filled with poetry.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I learn from the internet that mobbing should not be confused with gang stalking. Mobbing is perpetrated by a closed, defined group, such as an academic department or poetry community. Gang stalking is perpetrated by government/corporate agencies. Black vans sit outside your apartment, trail you down the street. Satellites beam voices into your brain via nanotechnology implanted in your skull. The voices are relentless and abrasive. They say everybody hates you. They urge you to harm yourself and others. Eventually you find out you are part of a vast government/corporate experiment whose goal is to break people, and then through mind control to create spies who don’t even know they’re spies. Mind control makes the best kind of spy because no matter how much the targeted individual is tortured, they can’t reveal secrets they don’t know they have. Their secrets are hidden deep within their brain behind an altar that only the programmers know how to unlock. The Russians have implanted nanotechnology inside Trump’s head, and that’s why he does their bidding. The programmers can kill you by remote control, make your heart clench, make you vomit liters of black goo. The whole thing’s set up to look like paranoid schizophrenia so that targeted individuals aren’t taken seriously. But these people hold conventions and tell their stories to the masses via websites and YouTube videos.  &lt;em&gt;Vice&lt;/em&gt; made a documentary about them. The psychological torture is so intense, many targeted individuals commit suicide. Some of them give in to the voices and go on a shooting spree. The internet is a cacophony of voices beaming love or hate at you, depending on your age race gender sexual preference body type politics. The internet can gather 2000 signatures against you overnight. You can be condemned on the merest wisp of data. Even if you aren’t the one who committed a crime, if you criticize mob action in the comment section of a poet’s Facebook feed, you’re labeled an apologist and you’re just as evil as the worst rapist or racist, and young women you barely know will hate you forever. If you protest they’ll hate you even more. If you block them on Facebook they’ll condemn you for silencing them. They’ll post screenshots of things you’ve written—out of context—and since you’re old and not as online savvy you don’t know how to make each post discrete, like a hologram with its context imbedded within it rather than depending on other posts for context. Powerful male mentors will boost their slanderous lies about you and no one will come to your defense except Brian Kim Stefans, who lives like a million miles away in Los Angeles. Locals will tell you privately they agree with you and they’re appalled by your treatment but they dare not say anything. And young guys who you thought were your friends will lecture you on your anti-feminist behavior. There’s only one response available to any guy who would lecture you on feminism and that’s fuck off, but still your heart breaks because you cared for them in an age-appropriate way, as if they were cute spaniels with big floppy ears. The poetry community you’ve been devoted to since the early 80s is no longer safe, and even those who didn’t mob you, you see them mobbing others, and this you cannot abide. On the internet you learn that when someone is directing negative energy at you, you should imagine yourself covered by mirrors and bounce that negative energy back to them. You should ground yourself by drinking chlorophyll, trace minerals, and specially ionized water.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
By harassing me does my stalker believe she’s saving Poetry or is she merely a sociopath lusting for blood? I read on the internet that stalking is like a long rape. Before such violence there is no place for obliqueness. Every piece I’ve ever written has centered around love, no matter how fucked up its manifestation. But this girl and her actions, I can find no love here to cling to, not even a spark. She’s like that evil queen who fed Snow White the poison apple. She’s a cliché of viciousness the internet has birthed. I sit at the computer fortressed in mirrors, my eyes peering through a narrow slit. I click the Mail icon. Something new has been ordered—three jars of moly bore treatment paste. I learn on the internet that your rub this paste on the inside of your rifle barrel in order to reduce friction for minimum fouling, faster, easier cleanup, and longer barrel life. My stalker posts Tinder screenshots from interested guys below her league and ridicules them. She posts provocative pictures of herself—flimsy teddies and wisps of panties she can pull aside in order to selfie her ass—and fantasizes the FBI agents she’s sure are surveilling her because she’s a radical are jerking off to her image. When I was a child I fantasized God was watching me, and so I would do cute things for God, inspired by the TV show &lt;em&gt;Candid Camera&lt;/em&gt;, which made Cold War surveillance culture fun. At any moment you could step out of ordinary life and do something adorable or amusing enough to be broadcast to all of America. With earbud attached to a coiled cord that trails from ear to back of neck and disappears into their dark jackets, FBI agents are forced to observe you. It is their job to remain professional and implacable, but your dirty talk on Twitter, your skimpy selfies are so damned seductive—flies zip open, well-scrubbed cocks pop out, sunglassed heads arc backwards in rapture. I learn on the internet that people who try to harm you are in fact possessed by negative entities, entities that they are unaware of. Therefore I say to my stalker—&lt;em&gt;You need to ground and clear yourself because you seem to be possessed. In your latest selfies you look awfully animalistic. You should drink some chlorophyll and wear a lead-lined hoodie to bed to protect yourself from the government/corporate complex that is beaming these terrible thoughts into your head.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- End of page --&gt;
&lt;!-- Start of Bottom Footer --&gt;

&lt;nav class=&quot;nav justify-content-center&quot; style=&quot;box-shadow: 0 2px 2px -2px rgba(0,0,0,0);&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;nav-container&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;//&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h2 class=&quot;nav-title&quot;&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul style=&quot;position: relative&quot;&gt;
      &lt;!-- &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;//&quot;&gt;Issue&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; --&gt;
      &lt;li class=&quot;nav-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;nav-link&quot; href=&quot;//2018-fall&quot;&gt;2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li class=&quot;nav-item&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;|&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li class=&quot;nav-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;nav-link&quot; href=&quot;//2019-fall&quot;&gt;2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li class=&quot;nav-item&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;|&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li class=&quot;nav-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;nav-link&quot; href=&quot;//people&quot;&gt;People&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li class=&quot;nav-item&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;|&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li class=&quot;nav-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;nav-link&quot; href=&quot;//about&quot;&gt;About&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/nav&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;container&quot;&gt;

  &lt;section id=&quot;sec1&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//dodie-bellamy/&quot;&gt;Dodie Bellamy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//The-Violence-of-the-Image/&quot;&gt;The Violence of the Image&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Stuff-My-Stalker-Has-Ordered-for-Me-Online/&quot;&gt;Stuff My Stalker Has Ordered for Me Online&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//may-lee-chai/&quot;&gt;May-lee Chai&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//White-Rabbits/&quot;&gt;White Rabbits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//tongo-eisen-martin/&quot;&gt;Tongo Eisen-Martin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Fish-With-Ambition-to-Become-the-River/&quot;&gt;Fish With Ambition to Become the River&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Two-Nights-on-16th-Street/&quot;&gt;Two Nights on 16th Street&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Many-Does-To-Go-Or-Turns-The-Pen/&quot;&gt;Many Doses To Go Or Turns the Pen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//jennifer-firestone/&quot;&gt;Jennifer Firestone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Selections-from-Ten/&quot;&gt;Selections from Ten&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/section&gt;
  &lt;section id=&quot;sec2&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//sheila-heti/&quot;&gt;Sheila Heti&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Literature-Against-Anxiety/&quot;&gt;Literature Against Anxiety&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//lorelei-lee/&quot;&gt;Lorelei Lee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Leaving-San-Francisco/&quot;&gt;Leaving San Francisco&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//miranda-mellis/&quot;&gt;Miranda Mellis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//The-Imperceptible-Utopia/&quot;&gt;The Imperceptible Utopia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//To-Not-Become-a-Pillar-of-Salt/&quot;&gt;To Not Become a Pillar of Salt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//christopher-merrill/&quot;&gt;Christopher Merrill&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Rustams-Throne/&quot;&gt;Rustam's Throne&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/section&gt;
  &lt;section id=&quot;sec3&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//katherine-min/&quot;&gt;Katherine Min&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//On-Being-a-Sprinter/&quot;&gt;On Being a Sprinter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//On-Being-Humpty-Dumpty/&quot;&gt;On Being Humpty Dumpty&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//laura-mullen/&quot;&gt;Laura Mullen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Scream/&quot;&gt;Scream&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Elsie-Disclaimer/&quot;&gt;Elsie (Disclaimer)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Elsie-The-Coward/&quot;&gt;Elsie The Coward&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Elsie-Doesnt-Mind/&quot;&gt;Elsie Doesn't Mind&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//El-C-the-C/&quot;&gt;El C the C&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//The-Imaginary-Begins/&quot;&gt;The Imaginary Begins&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//C-Section/&quot;&gt;C Section&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Queen-of-Muses/&quot;&gt;Queen of Muses&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//ron-silliman/&quot;&gt;Ron Silliman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//from-Parrot-Eyes-Lust/&quot;&gt;from Parrot Eyes Lust&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//ross-simonini/&quot;&gt;Ross Simonini&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Interview-with-Paul-McCarthy/&quot;&gt;Legs Spread, Mask On:  Reflections on Snow White, Deleuze, and Late Capitalism&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/section&gt;
  &lt;section id=&quot;sec4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//john-yau/&quot;&gt;John Yau&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//The-Presidents-Second-Telegram/&quot;&gt;The President's Second Telegram&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//The-Presidents-Telegram-3/&quot;&gt;The President's Telegram (3)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//The-Congressmans-Explination/&quot;&gt;The Congressman's Explanation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/section&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Dodie Bellamy</name></author><category term="20181111" /><summary type="html">Last month the 1959 low-budget monster movie Behemoth was on TV. I watched just the ending. The Behemoth, which looks like an elongated dinosaur with bulgy eyes, wiggles mechanically through the ocean. It’s way bigger than the submarine that’s trying to destroy it. Wham! It bashes against the side of the sub and water starts leaking from an overhead pipe, provoking tense meaningful eye contact between the two officers manning the controls. They maneuver for a better aim. One yells, “Fire!” and the other grits his teeth and presses a plunger, unloading a bomb that hits the monster in the head. It thrashes and sinks. “That’s it?” I thought. “They killed the thing with one shot?” These days it would take at least 15 minutes of fast-cut struggle, for we citizens of the 21st century have learned that evil does not die easily. No longer is evil focused like a bad tooth you can root out and get on with your good life. Increasingly diffuse, the Big Scary now spreads across networks, sprouting anywhere. We have global warming; we have public executions that shock without warning; we have toxic waters, honey bees threatened with extinction, warnings of plague. In the White House, Americans have installed an irrational, lying, unaccountable crook who rages against “radical Islamic terrorists,” an embarrassingly redundant term. Isn’t radical implied in terrorist? Have you ever heard of a middle brow terrorist? A centrist terrorist? A give-a-cop-a-can-of-Pepsi-and-heal-the-world terrorist? When you’re an American, you’ve got so much to be embarrassed about. The U.S. has become a very stupid country, and stupidity married to power is danger squared. We’ve given a buffoon the nuclear code. To be radical you need a wall to bounce your radicalism off of. When you live in a soup of cover ups, corruption, and general smarminess, is it possible to clear the mire enough to even find that wall? Those on the radical left claim—and rightly so—that global capitalism is the enemy. But late capitalism is a slippery beast, able to incorporate just about anything into its ravenous maw and spit it back out with a price tag attached. Blind, profit-driven virulence has infiltrated everything, its poison creeping both inside and outside of us. The Behemoth has swallowed the submarine and here we are, flailing in the slimy dark. In another 1950s cult favorite, The Wild One, a dancing blonde asks biker Marlon Brando, “Hey, Johnny, what are you rebelling against?” He bongos the top of a jukebox and snarls, “Whatta ya got?” What do we “got”? That is the central question facing us today. Without a focus, without a specific monster in mind to boom boom boom, radical enthusiasm can grind down to depression. We stop reading the news; we post pix of cats on Facebook, flowers on Instagram, obsessively checking for Likes. Or, like overcrowded rodents, we attack one another. I’ve got a stalker. I used to be her favorite writer, but when I posted bad opinions in the comments box of another poet’s Facebook thread, her admiration switched to disdain. She instantly hated me and all I stood for, even things I didn’t realize I stood for, and she began an assault across social media, ridiculing and accusing me. I find it difficult, today, to forgive the poets who left encouraging comments for her. I felt shunned and despised, like there was no love in the world for me. Presently emails from online shopping sites began appearing in my in-box, confirming orders I didn’t order, informing me my credit card had been declined. My stalker is a monster. She wouldn’t argue with this. Making herself into a monster makes her feel special. It is difficult for the entitled to feel special. Tattoos and heavy eyeliner and revealing little dresses—everybody—even fat girls—has those. She posts pictures of her ass to social media; she likes pastries and favors the word “super.” My stalker is a bully. A bully can smell someone who has been previously bullied—the bully and the bullied fit together like jigsaw puzzle pieces. I imagine her alone in the middle of the night, ashtray on her nightstand overflowing with butts, drunk, or buzzed on Adderall, maybe both, afraid to sleep due to last night’s bout of sleep paralysis, the tension is unbearable—tight jaw compacted heart—she searches for something crappy online—adds it to her shopping cart, enters my name address phone number, which she copied down the summer she interned for that radical indie press—her taut little body vibrates as she enters a fake credit card number, presses the PLACE ORDER button, pummeling me with hubcaps peonies guitar strings silk sock liners—what a fucking rush what a release—almost as good as the burst she gets when she slices her inner thigh with a razor blade—it’s like she’s sending me all her pain, her disappointment her god-awful ordinariness. Afterwards she feels a terrible intimacy, that of the torturer who comes to love her victim. With the election of Trump, poets decided that the only acceptable way to depict an American flag was upside down. When a provocateur poet posted a flag rightside up on Instagram, there was an angry Facebook thread about it. Poet A said that if he had known the flag poet was so fucked up, he never would have had him read in his series. Poets B and C proposed informing the flag poet’s employer about the offense and getting him fired. None of the poets noticed that the posted flag wasn’t a real American flag, but the fake Chinese-made flag that had been in the news, the one that unwitting patriots had purchased, with too many stars. Kevin back channeled poet B and pointed this out: That is not the regular flag. It has far too many stars. It is the 61-star flag that indicates the alternate history of America. Whether or not that’s a good thing or a bad depends how you feel about the flag today, and if you believe that the U.S. took a wrong turn somewhere back in history. The regular flag has only 50 stars—supposedly for each state in the union. However, poet B didn’t back down. He said he couldn’t understand what a 61-star flag would signify. He said that regardless of the flag poet’s intention, to be oblique on something this sensitive was aggressive, and the rightside up flag still reinscribed violence. If one is vague, poets will project the worst into your words. If you refer to a person but don’t name names, poets will assume it’s themselves or someone you’d never dream of. At Alley Cat Books the reader launches into a poem so politically correct you could bounce a dime off of it, political in all the right ways—and a poet in the audience starts nodding his head wildly back and forth as if it were a rattle. The rest of the reading he has a normal head. Political writing is straightforward, plain, and “learned,” prefaced by a declaration of the author’s identity markers. As a white cis American working class college-educated Baby Boomer who lives in California and prefers unoaked Chardonnay. … Political writing is careful about who owns what experience. Someone tweets: She doesn’t have the right to talk about that, and you feel shame. When a poet rants against me and the politics of my writing on Facebook, she begins with “What kind of woman would. …” What kind of woman implies a correct, proper version of femaleness—and I—not being that kind of woman—have crossed over into an impossible otherness. It doesn’t matter what else she goes on to accuse me of, What kind of woman has declared me an abomination. Since childhood I’ve been criticized for my nonstandard female embodiment. I was savage and unruly, clomping through life like a bull—and now I’m an old white feminist—an oppressor in a pink pussy hat. The Facebook poet’s curses scatter across my features like the points in facial recognition software, a surveillance grid that hardens on my face like a mask. No expression is possible in the tightness of her projections. Thought criminals need to be rooted out and shunned, the dead as well as the living. Cindy Sherman. Gandhi. Marjorie Perloff. Walt Whitman. And what I assume you shall assume,/ For every atom belonging to me as good belongs to you. Community walks within me and thus I contain both criminal and accuser. The idiocy of the American government, I contain that as well. In a muck of warring poets, I spew that war. Heriberto Yépez: Networks are both migrants and the gatekeepers. The madness of social media, it too walks within me. I operate in the dangerous and contradictory realm of the in-between. Neither goddess nor heroine, I am an old white feminist, a shriveled hag envious of my stalker’s fertility and youthful beauty. My hair is coarse and unkempt; my long hanging dugs bounce about like phalluses. I befoul Poetry with my personal essays, which are riddled with superstition, deceit, defective intelligence, lust, and debauchery. I am simultaneously horrific and ridiculous. My politics are so odious I’ve made pacts with rapists. Though he’s taken the form of a goat, I kiss the abuser’s backside; I apologize for him. In a skit called “Silver Surfers,” Tracey Ullman plays a teacher who shows seniors how to troll the internet. A woman says she’d like to see her grandson’s YouTube channel. Tracey turns on a video of a grade school boy demonstrating something. She notes how the video is amateurish in quality, and tells the class that when you see somebody getting it wrong online it’s important to point it out to them. Tracey instructs the class to click the thumbs down button—or if they want to make it more personal to post a comment, using a fake name, in which they say either he has a voice like a girl or everyone here wishes he were dead. Tracey types on the grandmother’s computer, “Wish you were dead, loser.” “It’s a real thrill when you click that send button,” she says. The internet, like late capitalism, is everywhere and nowhere. My stalker sends me objects that are not objects. They’re images I keep trying to push into language. According to capitalism, what you own you are. Lawn plants, chenille bedspread, frilly dresses, Forest Friends felt Christmas ornament kit, fish pond water conditioner, hubcaps. What is the stalker saying to/about me through these suburban talismans? According to capitalism, whoever controls images controls the world. I say to my psychic, I think I know who’s been stalking me, but I’m not sure. My psychic says, you know. How can I control these images that have been thrust upon me? I imagine a woman who wears floral dresses, a widow with a four-year old toddler. She loved her husband and always wears a peridot pendant that contains a bit of his ashes. She’s a photographer who plays the cello and drives a motorcycle. Alone in the house she feels vulnerable, so she keeps a gun under her pillow. She has a home office, a file box where she stores her photos. She’s femmy and a bit old fashioned. She sleeps under a tufted chenille bedspread; she uses face firming creams and bikini exfoliators. She’s trying to fix herself up to get another man. She gardens, preferring bulb plants from Holland—so she lives somewhere with a yard, a rural or suburban landscape. People do not suspect her wildness—the gun, the motorcycle—but it’s there waiting to take over. She likes bargains, preferring to buy things on sale, with coupon codes or open boxes. She has a Blu-ray player to help her through her lonely nights. Or maybe she met a man who owns a gun. He’s a rebel who deserves her bikini-groomed snatch. This new man likes porn; when she’s ready he plans to share some with her on the Samsung Blu-ray player he noticed in the living room. They sit in her garden with its lush greens, irises, and peonies, holding hands, kissing lightly, then more and more passionately. Let’s make it the guy who has the motorcycle. He’s a Marlon Brando type—a vet who’s living off of disability—going to art school in photography, and these things my stalker ordered are gifts for him, the wheel, the gun cleaner, the camera. She drives a car—a fully restored 61 Dodge Polara, which totally impresses the vet. That’s how they met—at a light he pulled up beside her on his motorcycle and asked her if she wanted to grab some coffee. After the coffee, the woman and the photographer fuck in the garden beside the koi pond, which is mercifully devoid of chlorine fumes thanks to Tetra Pond AquaSafe Tap Water Conditioner. Their sex is protected from nosey neighbors by a clump of kingsize hostas. The female koi are named after female science fiction writers, Doris Lessing, Octavia Butler; the male fish are named after 20th century avant garde composers, Boulez, Webern. Last week raccoons ate Ursula K. Le Guin, and before that they got Joanna Russ and Schoenberg, so that the woman is considering replacing the koi with a cheaper species, such as goldfish. The vet’s cock is pink and clean, squeaky clean like the Army taught him to keep it in their anti-VD training videos, well-scrubbed as his gun, the barrel of which he regularly plunges with Brownells Moly Bore Treatment Paste. The woman’s Diane von Furstenberg dress is pushed up to her waist. The vet pulls out his Nikon Coolpix and shoots a close up of the twig and gravel scratches on her ass. The Samsung Blu-ray player blasts “Bang a Gong.” HUBCAP DIAMOND STAR HALO. According to capitalism, accessories are personality. Commodities morph into character traits, morph into narrative momentum. Personal memories and product reviews on Amazon provide supplemental details. My fuck scene would be more erotic if there were more of a buildup but the woman is always ready. Too eager, perhaps. She can come without touching herself. Her cunt is so strong it could lift barbells, if she owned any. Sometimes the photographer complains she’s clenching him too tightly, but her cunt is ravenous for him, wants to absorb every drop his cock can offer. Afterwards she doesn’t wash, enjoying his semen smeared over her legs and belly, dripping out of her, and besides, the stalker hasn’t ordered her any soap. The first target of massive internet shaming and harassment was Monica Lewinsky, in 1998. She was 22 years old and, being the first, she had no context or support to help her cope. These days she finds comfort and purpose in her work with anti-harassment and bullying organizations. Her taped phone conversations with Linda Tripp are available on YouTube, hours of rambling female intimacy. I envy the closeness of the two women, the way they coddle the micro details of one another’s lives—everything from the temptation of donuts at the hairdresser—Monica’s favorite is white frosting with multi-colored sprinkles—to why won’t Bill call me. The conversations begin after Clinton has dumped Monica and track her heartbreak and desperate attempts to contact him. I’d love to have a girlfriend I could talk to endlessly about all my shit—someone as doting and supportive as Linda, someone who would slather me with such love. The betrayal by Tripp alone would devastate anyone—and that’s just a footnote to Monica’s collapse. If old white feminists ruled the world, one woman defiling another would be a capital offense. On Facebook, a male poet posts a photo of a naked man striding down the street. In the comments section, a female poet writes she finds the photo so upsetting her hands are shaking, and she just has to speak out. She’s decided the person in the photo is a mentally ill homeless man—even though there is nothing in the photo or the male poet’s post that announces that. Her extreme reaction to her (own) invented narrative prompts her to condemn the male poet and the hundred people who liked the image. I read on the internet that suggesting self-control online is tone policing, and I am wrong to go there. Maybe she’s right, we’re all a bunch of assholes laughing at the disenfranchised—or maybe he’s a gay nudist—in San Francisco it’s not uncommon to see naked men walking down the street, alone or in groups. The photo is of the man’s back, taken at a distance, maybe he has a glittering gold tube sock stuck on his cock. I’ve seen so many men with socks on their cocks—including panhandling teens on Castro Street. To get more money, I assume. No matter how much you stare at the image, it refuses to cough up more clues. Is it possible to keep your righteous fingers away from the keyboard? Is it possible to live without diminishing or oppressing another? Jain ascetics with soft broomsmade of shed peacock feathers, gently sweeping the ground lest they step on an insect. What are the limits of reverence? We make soup, we write tight little narratives where all messy threads are tied up, neatly, at the end. We read books on organizing our home. Rooms turn vast with order, with simplicity. We have only what we need, what we cherish, and there is a place for everything we own. Possessions are instantly findable and they are happy to serve us. The stalker destroys time, categories, and meaning, locking memories and dreams in the present moment. The mind strains against the body to push thoughts out. Everything is impure. The daily taunts and jeers I experienced as a child are happening right now right here. I’m pooping my guts out, taking slow breaths against the pain. My body is twisting my subjectivity, wringing it out like one of those old-time washing machines my grandmother had. Whenever anyone laughs they are laughing at me. The stalker has broken the frame. The process of writing this essay creates a new frame that proves I am capable of at least the most basic adult human functioning. How do you express trauma when linearity fails you? You order products online for your enemy. When the past possesses the present you enter the now now now of spurting adrenaline, and your irises spin like pinwheels. The pix shriek nobody wants you here the pix shriek you are hated everybody hates you. I publish a piece in a journal my stalker has also published in. I imagine her reading it with scorn, searching for bits out of context she can use to destroy me. “Dodie Bellamy said” becomes a tagline to ruin. On Nashville, Will, the gay character, is being bashed on Twitter and bam! his trauma is my trauma panic blots out the present like one of those bags terrorists shove over a captive’s head. I am forever a child useless and humiliated. I am a radiant pink clit inflamed by the eros of my stalker’s loathing. My stalker hates capitalism. I believe she hates capitalism more than she hates me. Headline on the internet: A majority of millennials now reject capitalism, poll shows. My stalker says that if she could have anything in the world she wished for, it would be to destroy capitalism. My stalker believes that by shoplifting items made by slaves in China she is fucking capitalism. When I was young I’d shoplift with friends but I was too much of a pussy to do it on my own. My friend Jackie—who was a pro—and I would come home with huge hauls of stuff, most of which I’d end up not wanting, and I had to figure out how to get rid of. Before we went on a run, we’d put on makeup and work dresses and little heels; our aesthetic was clueless middle class bargain hunter. Jackie’s first rule: no backpacks or large purses while shoplifting. We carried moderately-sized shoulder bags. They looked like they couldn’t hold much of anything—but you’d be surprised. I once smashed a fluffy pink prom dress into one. Jackie’s second rule was entitlement. When she found a stainless steel fish poacher she liked, she just picked it up and marched out of Macy’s with it, and nobody blinked. Despite its heart-thumping arousal, hours of nonstop shoplifting was exhausting. I felt buried in commodity culture and the treadmill of consumption that drives capitalism’s insatiable thrust. It was gross. When Jackie and I returned to my apartment, we dumped our haul onto my bed in a jumbled mountain, and then we belly-flopped onto it, shrieking, carefree as dogs rolling around in shit. One night, over a period two hours, thirteen things were ordered in my name, each from a different website. Then a coupleof hours later, another item, bringing the total to fourteen in one evening. Could one person possibly have ordered this much, this quickly? Or was somebody throwing a Harass Dodie party? I sat down at my desk and started emailing the companies—This order is fraudulent. I also downloaded the product photos per artist friend Kristina Lee Podesva’s suggestion. When I told her about my stalker, excitement spread across Kristina’s face and she exclaimed, “Document this!” The order confirmations were coming in so furiously I couldn’t keep up. I could only imagine that the person on the other end was tweaking. I checked my stalker’s Twitter feed. She tweeted before the ordering frenzy began and then not again until ten or fifteen minutes after it ended, when she wrote—My mother just asked me if I was on heroin. A few minutes later she tweeted—I’m reading in Philadelphia, if you come bring me flowers—peonies. Peony bulbs were one of the fourteen items. The world goes crazy with connection. I say to my psychic, I think I know who it is, but I’m not sure. My psychic says, you know. My stalker sends me a widow’s walk and a necklace to contain the ashes of a loved one—is she casting a spell of doom on me? What does an office chair mean? It requires work for me to write back to all these companies, but it also requires a hell of a lot of commitment and focused attention for her to order all this stuff. Her curated images are about potential, about our post-industrial condition, in which we sit at machines pushing around bytes, alone, longing to reach out. Glamor shots of merchandise hail her and she clicks them with the grammarless fever of a rat clicking a food-delivery lever. Eventually the image objects arrive on my computer and I click them with confusion and fear and anger, but also with a twinge of pleasure that reminds me of playing Monument Valley, my bumbling attempts to navigate a twisting architecture whose rules endlessly elude. Objects speak with the indeterminacy of a cry, garbled like puppets with their lips sewn shut. Yet it’s impossible not to narrativize them. To the protest, my stalker wears cotton toddler panties stretched tight across her cooch. Beneath her sheer Diane Von Furstenberg dress, areolas bloom, lush pink peonies. Comrades and government infiltrators alike find her unbearably sexy. Anything you send a writer is a gift. A suicidal young woman pulls up on a motorcycle. I rub her face into my desiccated crotch, suck the bloom from her cheeks and cough up bile. My breath is so foul sperm curdles and young Marxists faint. I too am not a bit tamed, I too am untranslatable,/ I sound my barbaric yawp over the roofs of the world. Before I became a middle class person I shopped only at thrift stores, so the clothes I owned were jeans, striped long-sleeved tees, and party dresses. When I got my first middle class job, I went to Macy’s and charged these awful outfits—polyester pants suits, etc.—I looked like a clown, a droopy professional clown. The middle class likes different things than the working class, but we all want things things things things—even homeless people in my neighborhood wheel shopping carts and suitcases overflowing with things. If capitalism were destroyed, would the homeless have better things? The viscosity of capitalism swallows us. We are never sure if we are inside or outside of it. It spreads over the globe making things stick together. I walk down the street wearing bits of China India Portugal Vietnam, and occasionally the USA. The ghosts of nameless workers vape from my silhouette, rendering me not one but many. My boss said my best middle class outfit was one I shoplifted with Jackie—a navy cashmere shift by Ralph Lauren. For the bourgeois subject wouldn’t guilt be a more appropriate response than hate? Perhaps guilt is what’s really behind the attacking of those perceived politically impure. Like a game of tag, you spread the cooties to those not deft enough to sidestep your fingering. Anyone who’s seen a zombie movie knows that when capitalism is destroyed we don’t get utopia. We get poetry bandits who police the perimeters. Law like a person has an unconscious. What my stalker really wants to destroy is the stink of trauma that wafts off of her. I provide a focal point for my stalker’s hate, a manageable target for the all-consuming vastness of her rage. If she didn’t have me, maybe she’d jump off a bridge or shoot up a post office, who knows. It’s the middle of the night and all this pressure is trapped in her body, enormous pressure she can’t release. She wants to sigh, to scream, to burst out crying. But nothing moves. Stuck in a limbo of angst, where sadness and fury are all mucked up together, ongoing and escalating, my stalker looks over her list of enemies. It’s Dodie tonight. People rarely do things just to be wicked—they act because they’re convinced they’ve encountered evil, convinced that innocents need protecting—or they perceive their livelihood is threatened—or a great wrong has been committed against them. Throughout history, horrible things—I don’t need to list them—have been done with God on our side, things that must have felt honorable at the time, but whose cruelty today shocks us. Powerful feelings can fuck you up, especially when fucked-up you feel you have the right to fuck up others. On the internet I read about a guy who stalked a woman for five years. Helen reported 125 incidents of harassment but the police did nothing until he attacked her with a pair of scissors, stabbing her multiple times on the neck, face, and back. It took a lot of googling to find out what Helen did to deserve her “living nightmare.” She met Joseph at a halfway house where she was recovering from an eating disorder. They became friends, until one night Joseph asked Helen to drive him and another friend to see a band called Carnaby Street. Helen didn’t feel up to it and said she’d text him if she changed her mind. Joseph felt stood up, and his affection for Helen instantly turned into burning hatred. So he vandalized her car, made silent phone calls, left a dead cat on her doorstep, smashed her windows, sent her letters calling her fat and rat-faced, spray-painted Die Helen across a brick wall, nearly killed her. Because she didn’t go to a concert. There is always a reason to destroy another. Anybody who needs a reason will find one. I was my stalker’s favorite writer until I posted a comment on a poet’s Facebook thread, three years ago. Before that I have no memory of having met her or heard of her. Though I think that’s not true; most likely I was in many rooms with her, rooms filled with poetry. I learn from the internet that mobbing should not be confused with gang stalking. Mobbing is perpetrated by a closed, defined group, such as an academic department or poetry community. Gang stalking is perpetrated by government/corporate agencies. Black vans sit outside your apartment, trail you down the street. Satellites beam voices into your brain via nanotechnology implanted in your skull. The voices are relentless and abrasive. They say everybody hates you. They urge you to harm yourself and others. Eventually you find out you are part of a vast government/corporate experiment whose goal is to break people, and then through mind control to create spies who don’t even know they’re spies. Mind control makes the best kind of spy because no matter how much the targeted individual is tortured, they can’t reveal secrets they don’t know they have. Their secrets are hidden deep within their brain behind an altar that only the programmers know how to unlock. The Russians have implanted nanotechnology inside Trump’s head, and that’s why he does their bidding. The programmers can kill you by remote control, make your heart clench, make you vomit liters of black goo. The whole thing’s set up to look like paranoid schizophrenia so that targeted individuals aren’t taken seriously. But these people hold conventions and tell their stories to the masses via websites and YouTube videos. Vice made a documentary about them. The psychological torture is so intense, many targeted individuals commit suicide. Some of them give in to the voices and go on a shooting spree. The internet is a cacophony of voices beaming love or hate at you, depending on your age race gender sexual preference body type politics. The internet can gather 2000 signatures against you overnight. You can be condemned on the merest wisp of data. Even if you aren’t the one who committed a crime, if you criticize mob action in the comment section of a poet’s Facebook feed, you’re labeled an apologist and you’re just as evil as the worst rapist or racist, and young women you barely know will hate you forever. If you protest they’ll hate you even more. If you block them on Facebook they’ll condemn you for silencing them. They’ll post screenshots of things you’ve written—out of context—and since you’re old and not as online savvy you don’t know how to make each post discrete, like a hologram with its context imbedded within it rather than depending on other posts for context. Powerful male mentors will boost their slanderous lies about you and no one will come to your defense except Brian Kim Stefans, who lives like a million miles away in Los Angeles. Locals will tell you privately they agree with you and they’re appalled by your treatment but they dare not say anything. And young guys who you thought were your friends will lecture you on your anti-feminist behavior. There’s only one response available to any guy who would lecture you on feminism and that’s fuck off, but still your heart breaks because you cared for them in an age-appropriate way, as if they were cute spaniels with big floppy ears. The poetry community you’ve been devoted to since the early 80s is no longer safe, and even those who didn’t mob you, you see them mobbing others, and this you cannot abide. On the internet you learn that when someone is directing negative energy at you, you should imagine yourself covered by mirrors and bounce that negative energy back to them. You should ground yourself by drinking chlorophyll, trace minerals, and specially ionized water. By harassing me does my stalker believe she’s saving Poetry or is she merely a sociopath lusting for blood? I read on the internet that stalking is like a long rape. Before such violence there is no place for obliqueness. Every piece I’ve ever written has centered around love, no matter how fucked up its manifestation. But this girl and her actions, I can find no love here to cling to, not even a spark. She’s like that evil queen who fed Snow White the poison apple. She’s a cliché of viciousness the internet has birthed. I sit at the computer fortressed in mirrors, my eyes peering through a narrow slit. I click the Mail icon. Something new has been ordered—three jars of moly bore treatment paste. I learn on the internet that your rub this paste on the inside of your rifle barrel in order to reduce friction for minimum fouling, faster, easier cleanup, and longer barrel life. My stalker posts Tinder screenshots from interested guys below her league and ridicules them. She posts provocative pictures of herself—flimsy teddies and wisps of panties she can pull aside in order to selfie her ass—and fantasizes the FBI agents she’s sure are surveilling her because she’s a radical are jerking off to her image. When I was a child I fantasized God was watching me, and so I would do cute things for God, inspired by the TV show Candid Camera, which made Cold War surveillance culture fun. At any moment you could step out of ordinary life and do something adorable or amusing enough to be broadcast to all of America. With earbud attached to a coiled cord that trails from ear to back of neck and disappears into their dark jackets, FBI agents are forced to observe you. It is their job to remain professional and implacable, but your dirty talk on Twitter, your skimpy selfies are so damned seductive—flies zip open, well-scrubbed cocks pop out, sunglassed heads arc backwards in rapture. I learn on the internet that people who try to harm you are in fact possessed by negative entities, entities that they are unaware of. Therefore I say to my stalker—You need to ground and clear yourself because you seem to be possessed. In your latest selfies you look awfully animalistic. You should drink some chlorophyll and wear a lead-lined hoodie to bed to protect yourself from the government/corporate complex that is beaming these terrible thoughts into your head.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The President’s Telegram (3)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/The-Presidents-Telegram-3/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The President’s Telegram (3)" /><published>2018-11-01T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-11-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/the-presidents-telegram-3</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/The-Presidents-Telegram-3/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
There are no words to express
&lt;br /&gt;
the horrible horrific happened
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Journalists, like all fear,
&lt;br /&gt;
should be attacked while doing their jobs
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
To the families of the violently, there are victims
&lt;br /&gt;
to express protect reduce regret your loss
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
There are jobs to pledge eternal support
&lt;br /&gt;
our horrible, horrible sorrow
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
When you are suffering
&lt;br /&gt;
we pledge warmest Best Wishes
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I’ve seen families express great sorrow
&lt;br /&gt;
for your eternal suffering
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- End of page --&gt;
&lt;!-- Start of Bottom Footer --&gt;

&lt;nav class=&quot;nav justify-content-center&quot; style=&quot;box-shadow: 0 2px 2px -2px rgba(0,0,0,0);&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;nav-container&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;//&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h2 class=&quot;nav-title&quot;&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul style=&quot;position: relative&quot;&gt;
      &lt;!-- &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;//&quot;&gt;Issue&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; --&gt;
      &lt;li class=&quot;nav-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;nav-link&quot; href=&quot;//2018-fall&quot;&gt;2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li class=&quot;nav-item&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;|&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li class=&quot;nav-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;nav-link&quot; href=&quot;//2019-fall&quot;&gt;2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li class=&quot;nav-item&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;|&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li class=&quot;nav-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;nav-link&quot; href=&quot;//people&quot;&gt;People&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li class=&quot;nav-item&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;|&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li class=&quot;nav-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;nav-link&quot; href=&quot;//about&quot;&gt;About&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/nav&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;container&quot;&gt;

  &lt;section id=&quot;sec1&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//dodie-bellamy/&quot;&gt;Dodie Bellamy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//The-Violence-of-the-Image/&quot;&gt;The Violence of the Image&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Stuff-My-Stalker-Has-Ordered-for-Me-Online/&quot;&gt;Stuff My Stalker Has Ordered for Me Online&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//may-lee-chai/&quot;&gt;May-lee Chai&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//White-Rabbits/&quot;&gt;White Rabbits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//tongo-eisen-martin/&quot;&gt;Tongo Eisen-Martin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Fish-With-Ambition-to-Become-the-River/&quot;&gt;Fish With Ambition to Become the River&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Two-Nights-on-16th-Street/&quot;&gt;Two Nights on 16th Street&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Many-Does-To-Go-Or-Turns-The-Pen/&quot;&gt;Many Doses To Go Or Turns the Pen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//jennifer-firestone/&quot;&gt;Jennifer Firestone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Selections-from-Ten/&quot;&gt;Selections from Ten&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/section&gt;
  &lt;section id=&quot;sec2&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//sheila-heti/&quot;&gt;Sheila Heti&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Literature-Against-Anxiety/&quot;&gt;Literature Against Anxiety&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//lorelei-lee/&quot;&gt;Lorelei Lee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Leaving-San-Francisco/&quot;&gt;Leaving San Francisco&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//miranda-mellis/&quot;&gt;Miranda Mellis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//The-Imperceptible-Utopia/&quot;&gt;The Imperceptible Utopia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//To-Not-Become-a-Pillar-of-Salt/&quot;&gt;To Not Become a Pillar of Salt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//christopher-merrill/&quot;&gt;Christopher Merrill&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Rustams-Throne/&quot;&gt;Rustam's Throne&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/section&gt;
  &lt;section id=&quot;sec3&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//katherine-min/&quot;&gt;Katherine Min&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//On-Being-a-Sprinter/&quot;&gt;On Being a Sprinter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//On-Being-Humpty-Dumpty/&quot;&gt;On Being Humpty Dumpty&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//laura-mullen/&quot;&gt;Laura Mullen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Scream/&quot;&gt;Scream&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Elsie-Disclaimer/&quot;&gt;Elsie (Disclaimer)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Elsie-The-Coward/&quot;&gt;Elsie The Coward&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Elsie-Doesnt-Mind/&quot;&gt;Elsie Doesn't Mind&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//El-C-the-C/&quot;&gt;El C the C&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//The-Imaginary-Begins/&quot;&gt;The Imaginary Begins&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//C-Section/&quot;&gt;C Section&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Queen-of-Muses/&quot;&gt;Queen of Muses&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//ron-silliman/&quot;&gt;Ron Silliman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//from-Parrot-Eyes-Lust/&quot;&gt;from Parrot Eyes Lust&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//ross-simonini/&quot;&gt;Ross Simonini&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//Interview-with-Paul-McCarthy/&quot;&gt;Legs Spread, Mask On:  Reflections on Snow White, Deleuze, and Late Capitalism&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/section&gt;
  &lt;section id=&quot;sec4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//john-yau/&quot;&gt;John Yau&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//The-Presidents-Second-Telegram/&quot;&gt;The President's Second Telegram&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//The-Presidents-Telegram-3/&quot;&gt;The President's Telegram (3)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: 'Work Sans','Segoe UI',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color:#000;&quot; href=&quot;//The-Congressmans-Explination/&quot;&gt;The Congressman's Explanation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/section&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>John Yau</name></author><category term="20181111" /><summary type="html">There are no words to express the horrible horrific happened Journalists, like all fear, should be attacked while doing their jobs To the families of the violently, there are victims to express protect reduce regret your loss There are jobs to pledge eternal support our horrible, horrible sorrow When you are suffering we pledge warmest Best Wishes I’ve seen families express great sorrow for your eternal suffering</summary></entry></feed>